You clean up very nicely,
if you don't mind me saying so.
I don't mind you saying so. Thanks.
You look...
pretty much the same as
you always look. Oh...
Really? Yes.
This is my date outfit. Really?
Is this your first date?
I mean, um, since your wife died?
Do I seem out of practice?
Hi. Hi.
Uh, my name's Gerard.
I'll be your server this evening.
Would you like to hear our specials?
I'm sorry to interrupt, Gerard,
but I'm getting a message from,
uh, your mother.
A J-- no, um, Janis. Yes.
Um...
I'm sorry for your loss.
She's happy now.
And she wants you to know that
she sends her deepest love.
And, um...
your Uncle...
Ed says, "Roll Tide."
Does that mean anything
to you--Roll Tide?
My mother's brother Edward.
He died five years ago.
He was a tight end at
Alabama in the '60s. Oh.
Uh, they're called
the Crimson Tide.
Uh, that's their rallying cry-
"Roll Tide." Oh.
Well, uh, I'd like to have
the soup Du jour and
the lamb, medium,
and the arugula salad and
the fish for the lady.
Thank you. You're welcome.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thanks.
What? Oh, come on.
You're so ferocious
in your lack of faith.
I mean, is it so hard to imagine
that I'm not putting on an act?
That--that I really
am what I say I am?
His mother sent a message.
I'm meant to help. That's all.
It happens to me all the time.
Okay.
I'm sorry.
Roll Tide.
Bad guys just keep on coming, huh?
I hate the Internet.
Listen, if you like, I can deal.
You go. No, it's okay.
It's just a Web alert
for when a name we're
interested in pops up.
Wayne?
What is it?
Oh.
This is not good.
Relax, it's-- it's just a hoax.
It's staged, almost certainly.
I didn't put-- uh, no. Yes.
No. No.
You went to jail,
really? Yes, I did.
What's so hard to believe?
For how long?
I was there for two days and
two very luxurious nights.
Uh-huh. Yeah.
And how'd you get out?
I just escaped.
Uh-huh. I don't believe you
for one second. It wasn't--
it wasn't that difficult.
It's all timing.
Uh-huh.
I'm not kidding. Okay. -Huh.
Excuse me. I have to
go to the bathroom.
Ah, thank you.
Hey.
Kristina, um...
Oh. I'm so sorry.
It's work.
Hello. Jane, you need to come
to the office right now.
It was posted on the
Internet an hour ago
on a popular notice board.
There's a message
that goes with it.
"I am becoming what
I was meant to be.
Your children's children
will worship me."
We don't know when or
where the video was made.
There appears to be an '08
Silverado parked outside the house,
so it's gotta be at
least that recent.
Has Red John made videos
or issued statements
like this before? No.
Oh, thank you. Excuse me.
Sorry to interrupt.
Oh. Hi, Kristina.
Uh, good to see you.
Yeah. That poor girl.
Yeah, yeah.
For what it's worth,
I'm getting a sense that
she died very recently.
Her body will be discovered very soon.
She's near water.
Does this feel like
Red John to you?
Uh, I'm not getting a read on that.
The whole Internet aspect is
interesting, though, isn't it?
I mean, why put it up there?
This clip's had over a million viewers.
A desire for fame?
Patrick, you're being very quiet.
What are you thinking?
Uh, I'd have to see
the crime scene.
C.H.P. just reported a
homicide in the Bay area.
Smiley face on the wall.
College student named
Marley Sparrow.
Roommate found her,
called it in about a half-hour ago.
Let's get ready to go.
Bay area?
Uh, yes. That is close to water.
That's, uh, that's uncanny.
Oh, come on. That's pretty good.
I am feeling a strong
connection to this case somehow.
Madeline, can we
have a word, please
Yeah.
Excuse us.
She's gonna ask if she
can come along with us.
Now obviously, that's your call.
But I hope that you refuse,
because I won't work with her.
I will quit.
What's your objection?
If she can help us, why not?
Nothing she says is more
than clever guesswork.
So she has essentially
the same skills as you,
without all the drama.
What's the deal?
Red John is mine.
Okay. Okay, I hear you. Thank you.
I'm sorry to interrupt.
Oh, please. Uh...
Um, I was going to
offer my services,
but I get the sense
Mr. Jane is telling you
that he won't work with me.
The last thing I want to do
is upset this investigation,
but if I have any more
feelings about the case,
could I call you? Of course,
Kristina.
Always be glad to
hear your thoughts.
Have a good night. Thank you.
Okay.
Listen, uh, I-
I completely understand.
No hard feelings. Okay.
That was an unusual date,
though, huh?
Yes, very. Thank you.
I'll see you soon, I hope.
Um, would you-- oh, yeah, sure.
Oh.
Bye. Bye.
Guys give me a minute, please.
Thank you.
Hey, Marley. We'll get
this sorted out for you.
Hey, hey, Patrick Jane.
Long time.
So qué pasa, dude?
My people need to do their thing.
I won't be long.
Oh.
You hoovering up the, uh,
ol' psychic ectoplasm?
Yeah, that's exactly
what I'm doing.
We have a schedule to keep,
amigo. Ticktock.
Sooner you're done fooling around,
sooner my people can
find actual clues.
She's from Iowa.
She played the guitar.
She liked dark chocolate,
sudoku and snowboarding.
Shy, but strong.
Honorable, modest.
Didn't drink or smoke.
Parents died when
she was very young.
And after college,
she wanted to go into family law
and help foster kids like herself.
Or become a singer.
She hadn't made up her mind yet.
Yeah, that's great, dude.
But where's Red John?
Oh, this wasn't Red John.
So you say.
So I say.
Jerk.
Oh, make sure you have your people
send those papers and
journals to the CBI office.
Will do. Thank you.
Marley was the best.
The best person.
A beautiful soul.
Rut you found her body, yes?
When you entered your house,
did you notice anything unusual
before you found the body?
Something missing or out of place? No,
I don't think so.
How long had you been gone?
Two days, snowboarding.
Marley was supposed to come,
but then her boyfriend was
coming over to see her,
so she stayed. Boyfriend's name?
Grady Shipp. He's a
policeman in San Francisco.
They've been dating for,
like, a month.
Okay. What was he like? Nice guy?
Marley really liked him a lot.
Said he was super nice
but I don't know.
We never actually met him. No?
She'd go to his place, mostly.
And when he came by here,
he'd wait for her in his car.
Weird, no?
I think Marley was
a bit embarrassed
for hooking up with a cop,
you know? Ah.
So she kept him on the down low.
Embarrassed, why?
Marley was cool.
And, well, cops are sort of
nerds with guns, aren't they?
Ruth, hello?
No offense.
Sorry.
Marley Sparrow?
Yes, I was her academic
advisor for two semesters.
Nice enough girl,
but not as clever as she
likes to think she is.
But none of 'em are, are they? Ha!
Did you notice any changes
in her behavior recently?
No. But nor do I pay
close attention.
They're all empty vessels
to be filled with knowledge.
Here is a horrible coincidence.
Last semester, I taught
a criminology elective.
Murder, myth and marketing-
the serial killer as commodity.
Red John was actually mentioned
in our class discussions.
Isn't that eerie? Who mentioned him?
What'd they say?
Oh, damned if I know.
It was eight or nine months ago.
Do you have a student
list from the class?
You know, I do. I do. Somewhere.
I do... We would love to
get a look at that list.
Thanks.
So there's no Grady Shipp with
any San Fran police agency.
There's no Grady Shipp, period.
There was a Grady Shipp once.
He killed and ate his
next-door neighbors
in Little Rock back in the '90s.
He was lethally injected
by the state of Arkansas in '02.
Huh. So Marley's boyfriend
doesn't want anybody
to see his face, and he named
himself after a cannibal.
That's two strikes against him.
Shame we don't have a
name or a description.
The roommate, Ruth, said that
he never got out of his car.
Maybe we can get a make
and model from her.
Grady Shipp.
In 1989, he did a 6-month spell
in the same wing at Lompoc
as Orval Tanner.
Orval Tanner? Red John's friend.
You have the entire Lompoc
prison registry in your head?
Well, only the relevant sections.
Wh-what does it mean? Is it a joke?
Marley's boyfriend is Red John.
That doesn't make any sense.
In the hunt for this beast known as "
Red John."
Well, he-- he's not a beast, Jackie.
He's a human being.
Now he has done terrible thing
bubuhe is still capable of redemption...
like all of us.
Red John...
If you're listening to us now,
I urge you to reach out and get help.
You can change.
What the hell are you thinking?!
Don't you understand who
you're dealing with?
I do understand, yes.
No, you don't.
Clearly, you don't understand.
I asked miss Frye here
so that I could fully
express my deep dismay.
I was speaking from the heart.
That may be, but you were
also hustling for business.
And that's okay, but you
present me now with a problem.
We don't have any obligation
to protect you, but--
I wasn't asking for protection.
It's completely unnecessary.
Red John is not coming after me.
Are you blind? You've
done exactly what I did.
I went on television and talked
about him as though I knew him,
and he killed my wife and child.
Patrick, he was punishing you
because you lied about him.
I was telling the truth.
He won't take offense with me.
He might even listen
to what I said.
In fact, I-I believe he will.
People do change, Patrick.
It's possible.
Agent Hightower, I'm truly
sorry for dismaying you.
Now if you'll excuse me,
I have some other appointments.
She needs 24-hour protection--
the best that you can provide.
The SAC P.D.
special protection unit
will provide security,
the CBI will be
on the inside,
bodyguarding miss Frye.
Jane and I will take
the first shift.
The next 24-hour rotation
will be split among us,
alternating with the Sparrow case.
Well, we're gonna have to stop
protecting her sooner or later.
That's when he'll go for her.
He'll just wait.
Van Pelt, what do you got?
We're looking for
Grady Shipp, right?
This is Marley's address book.
That's different writing.
Maybe that's Grady
Shipp himself. Can I?
Keep digging. Rigsby, take Cho with you.
Check it out. Yeah, you got it.
Hello?
Lapping sounds)
Blood. Yep.
Pig's blood, maybe.
For practice?
Police! Stop!
I'll call it in.
What is it?
A lens cap.
Interesting.
Practicing the Red John symbol,
and not just watching
us pursue him,
but filming the pursuit.
What does it mean?
It means Marley Sparrow's killer
loves cameras. He's a voyeur...
A fanboy,
a slasher movie geek. Huh.
Great. But where does
that take us now?
Like in a car? Well,
try the campus film club.
All right.
Nice place, huh? Tasteful.
To me, it looks like we're
about to pay way too much money
to get our legs waxed. Hmm.
Hi. I was just making some lunch.
Would you like something to eat?
Sure, thanks.
I'm good. Thanks.
Patrick, uh, on reflection,
I'm truly sorry for the
situation I put you in.
I hadn't thought through
your involvement.
All right, all right.
I-I-I'll eat some lunch.
Just please don't make a fuss.
Miss Ketchum?
Oh, policemen.
Okay. I knew I'd forgotten
something. Uh...
Okay.
There it is.
I thought for sure I'd sent that.
Sent what? Uhuh, the class list
of the students in
my criminology class.
Your colleague had asked for it.
And you're chair of
the film club also?
I have that honor. You know what?
I have the film club
register here as well.
Okay...
Yes, yes. Would you like to see it?
Yes. That would be, uh, good.
Okay.
Ah, there you go.
And where were you Tuesday night,
miss Ketchum?
Oh, how thrilling!
Am I a suspect? Are you?
Well...
I'd like to think I can still
summon that kind of passion.
So where were you?
Home. Alone.
Reading a murder mystery, actually.
Now there's only one name on
both lists--Wesley Blankfein.
Oh, wait. You just made a face.
Well, he is a sweet boy.
Rather a good actor, actually.
But, uh... strange.
Strange? How? I can't
really put my finger on it.
It's a look in his eyes.
Yep, that's him.
I remember when he moved in.
I mentioned to him
he was a little older
than most of our students,
and he said he needed to
escape from his mother.
Which, uh, I thought
was an odd response.
And when did you last see him? Uh,
three weeks ago...
Excuse me. Uh, maybe.
I figured he had a girlfriend.
Nothin here. Oh, hey, Dylan.
Oh, hey, you guys. Quick question.
Now you guys said
Marley's boyfriend
waited for her outside
in a car? Yes.
Do you recall what
type of car he drove?
Um, it was black,  I think.
I'm bad with cars.
It was a-- it was a black S.U.V.
What car did Blankfein drive? Uh,
he didn't have a car.
Huh. Okay.
Try locating Blankfein's mother.
Maybe she knows where he is.
All right. Let me know.
Wesley Blankfein's in the wind.
Looks like he might be good for this.
I don't think so.
Marley made contact with me.
The name "Blankfein"
doesn't resonate.
Marley made contact with you? Yes.
Of course. Uh, I think
we might have had enough of your
crime-fighting skills, Kristina.
Might be best to stick
to the crystal therapy
and the, uh... foot massages?
Reflexology. Right.
Reflexology.
This is Lisbon.
Agent Senton, FBI.
Yeah, we got a case
here in Lake Tahoe.
Looks like your boy Red John.
Victim's name is
a Jacqueline Sandoval.
You wanna come take a look?
You can smile your arrogant smile
and act like you know
everything about everything,
but you don't.
There are whole worlds
that you can't even begin to understand.
Synchronized swimming
is, uh, the only world
that Springs to mind.
But I'm sure you're right.
There may be many others.
What's the matter?
Red John killed the woman
who interviewed you.
Oh, my God.
It's Red John, all right.
Okay, uh, I'll reach
out to the feds.
I'll make sure they keep us in the loop.
We gotta get back to Kristina Frye's place.
There are cops all around her house.
Van Pelt is with her,
and there's other CBI agents
on their way. She's safe.
I am confident Red John's
not gonna go there.
That is exactly why he might.
If he does, we'll get him.
You really wanna hang
out at Kristina's house,
waiting for Red John to show up?
Let's just go back to the office,
and we'll work the Marley Sparrow case.
There's nothing useful that I can do there.
This Blankfein character-
he looks good for it, right? Fine.
Go and wait for Red John.
It's not a good idea, though.
Hey, we're in Nevada.
You can't just walk
off and leave me here.
Hey. Hey, boss.
So Wesley Blankfein's mother
is Myra Hauser-Blankfein.
Address in Franklin heights.
And she owns a black S.U.V.
Like Grady Shipp drives.
Good. Go check her out.
Now? Well, it's a long drive.
You leave now, you'll
be there by the morning.
Grace, thank you.
How you doing?
I'm doing fine.
Red John certainly made his point.
Quite possibly,
he'll leave things be now.
I know he will.
I have a clear vision of him.
He needs to create fear,
that's all.
He's done that now,
and he feels calm.
And I'm perfectly safe.
Will you just stop that nonsense?
You wanted to promote
your psychic business,
and--and you made a big mistake.
Now will you just-
will you please just own it?!
Why are you here?
I am here because I
want to protect you.
And how are you gonna protect me?
If Red John comes through
that door right now,
what are you gonna do, hypnotize him?
I will do what I need to do.
If Red John wants to
reach me, he will.
I choose to believe
that he doesn't want to.
Now please, go away. I'm gone.
Uh, you're wasting your time.
Ma'am, we're looking for Mrs.
Blankfein and her son. Gone.
And left the cats to starve.
It's not right.
Do you know where they went? Uh, nope.
Never leaves before. Never.
Every day, 11:00,
like a machine,
she's watching her TV shows.
Three days now I hear nothing.
Quiet like the grave.
How about her son Wesley?
Have you seen him?
Nope. Gone, too.
Did it occur to you that Mrs.
Blankfein might be dead in there?
Yes, it did.
But there'd be a smell,
wouldn't there, if she was dead?
Step back inside, please, ma'am.
You good? Yeah.
Bedroom's clear.
Rigsby.
Oh, jeez.
"G.S." Grady Shipp.
Bingo.
Inside the mind of
Wesley Blankfein--
A.K.A. Grady Shipp. Not pretty.
What it looks like--
he's obsessed with Marley,
so he builds a shrine
and he fakes up all these
photos of them together.
Then he tries to turn the
fantasy into reality,
and posing as Grady Shipp,
asks her out,
and she says yes. Big mistake.
Fantasy and reality collide,
and she dies. Sounds about right.
Where the hell is he? Uh,
where's his mom?
You didn't find anything useful in
the apartment? No computer, nothing?
No. A lot of cats.
Now the pictures of Marley-
they were all taken
at different times and places.
The pictures of Wesley
were all taken in the same place.
Nowhere we've been.
Maybe that's a safe house for him.
Nothing to say where it is, though.
Jane, you wanna take a look?
See if you see anything useful? Huh?
Yeah, sure.
If you like.
Hmm.
Yep. And...
There's a photo of Wesley
with a sign in the distance--
a yellow "kc" backward on a pole.
His--his shadow is
pointing right to it.
Yeah. It's way small back there,
but I see it.
Yeah, that's the logo
for Kenny's Chili--
Southern California
fast food chain.
There's about 50 or so outlets.
You memorize trademarks?
Well, with Wesley's long
shadow and the golden light,
that would say afternoon.
And sun is in the West,
so that puts Kenny's due
East of this location--
about a block and a half, I'd say.
Huh. He's right.
50 or so outlets?
Hardware store and a liquor store
on the block right next to it.
That should narrow it down.
I'll get on it.
Thank you. Oh. No.
You should make that call.
What call? Right.
Like I'm not a Detective, too?
Hey, Jane. It's Grace.
Kristina's taking a nap.
I can get her for you if you l like.
I'd appreciate that, Grace.
Thank you.
Kristina?
Kristina,
it's Jane for you.
Open the door.
Kristi? ? Kristina?
Kristina?!
Kristina
How did Kristina get past
the guards? We don't know.
But she also packed a bag,
she took her passport
and her credit cards,
so we can assume she wasn't abducted.
No, no, no, no.
You--you-- you can't assume.
Red John could've
gotten in and taken her.
Maybe. But the likelihood is she
panicked and ran somewhere to hide.
yeah. Or--or--or maybe
he lured her out somehow.
We'll check the phone records.
Let's start contacting her
relatives and friends.
She's out there somewhere. Forgive me,
Agent Lisbon, but delay that order.
The search for Kristina
Frye will now be conducted
by the missing persons unit. What?
They're the best at what they do.
They will find her
if she can be found.
And, Van Pelt, snap out of it.
Wasn't your fault.
Yes, ma'am, but--
move on.
All right. Where are we on
the Marley Sparrow case?
We have a suspect at large by
the name of Wesley Blankfein.
He's been obsessed with both
Red John and Marley Sparrow.
He seems to have
created an alter ego
by the name of Grady Shipp.
It's after a killer with Red
John connections. Any leads?
Well, off photos he took,
we've id'd six possible locations
for what we assume is
Blankfein's safe house.
It's pretty much a long shot,
but it's all we have.
Okay. All right. Go to it.
Let's start divvying
up the locations.
Cho, you take Riverside county.
Bring Rigsby with you.
Van Pelt and I will take the
San Bernardino locations.
Jane, you stay here. Take a break.
I don't need a break.
I think you do.
I-I-I'd rather keep active.
You're too hyped up to
be out in the field.
Oh, that's nonsense.
I agree with Lisbon. Get some rest.
Some rest? Oh, just...
Lie down and catch up on some z's.
Kick back with a good book. Rest?
I'm fine.
Debatable.
Do you want me to ask the psych
counselor for an evaluation?
Sorry.
Leave a message.
I'll call you back.
Lisbon, it's Jane. Uh, I found it.
It's 52 north Esperanza.
Hotel Del corona in Salinger Mill.
Uh, I am gonna...
Uh, I-I'm gonna wait for you
at, uh, Kenny's
Okay? Give me a call when
you get this message.
Thank you.
Ha
Welcome, Detective.
I'm Grady Shipp.
So good of you to come visit me.
You're a lucky man.
Very lucky.
Tonight...
You will have the dying honor...
Can we do that again?
Tonight...
You will have the honor of dying
as a sacrifice
to the Holy master, Red John.
Behold...
The blood sacrament
of the master.
Stop. You wanna try that again?
Huh? Just t-try it again.
Uh, say it like you mean it.
You know, where's the passion gone?
Behold the blood
sacrament of the master.
Oh, n-n-no. I'm not--I'm not-
I'm not buying it. Come on.
Just--just stofofoa a c
and think--think about
what you're doing here,
and then we'll start
again from the top, okay?
Uh... it's all right, Wesley.
I know what's going on.
They've got your mother,
don't they?
Yeah. How'd you know?
They're forcing you to play a part
in their sick little movie. Yes.
You're playing the part
of Grady Shipp, right?
Yes.
It's okay. It's okay.
Dylan! Ruth!
We need to talk.
Thank you very much
for totally ruining
a freaking brilliant scene,
you jerk.
Hush, Dyl.
How did you know it was us?
Well, you were the only people
that mentioned Grady Shipp.
He was your creation.
And it was you that killed Marley,
wasn't it, Dylan?
Wesley couldn't hurt a fly.
It was a truly sick
individual that did that.
It was me, actually.
Oh.
Dyl's much better with the camera,
and Marley...
Deserved what she got,
pious little bitch.
Keep the camera running.
This is all good stuff.
No offense, but you wouldn't know good
stuff if it smacked you in the face.
This is just a corny slasher movie.
Yeah, but real, dude.
Real blood. Real guts.
Yours. Wesley, let's, uh,
wrap this scene up now, okay?
Gonna pick it up right at the end--
"behold the blood," et cetera,
and then stab this sucker, okay?
I don't know. That's it.
What? Wh-what are you--not--no!
Okay, this--this man is dead.
Okay, the only question is
whether you and your mom want
to live or you want to die
like him, okay?
That's your choice here.
These people are nuttier
than a fruitcake.
They're gonna kill you regardless.
You don't have to do this.
We are not monsters, Wesley.
We're artists.
We are making art.
When the movie's done, of course
you and your mom are free to go,
with our gratitude for your help.
Stay calm.
"Behold the blood." Wesley.
I'm sorry.
Wesley. Wesley, Wesley, hey.
Behold... No, Wesley.
The blood sacrament...
No. It's okay. Of the master!
Wesley!
If there's one thing
I can't tolerate,
it's cheap imitations of my work.
Ohh.
No!
Do you know who I am?
Yes.
"Tiger, tiger, burning bright..."
"In the forests of the night,
"what immortal hand or eye
could frame thy fearful symmetry?"
Aah!
I almost forgot.
Kristina would want
me to send her love.
She's very fond of you,
despite your differences.
Roll Tide.
You okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
You're sure he said nothing?
Nothing at all?
Nothing.
"Tiger, tiger,
"burning bright...
"In the forests of the night,
"what immortal hand or eye
could frame thy fearful symmetry?"
Uploaded by
-klepal (GenieGr)-
www.tvsubtitles.net