Where the hell is he, Stace?
Don't worry, Mr. Lynch.
I'm sure he'll be here soon.
Yeah, well, this is ridiculous.
I mean, he goes on in
less than five minutes.
It's all right, Mr.
Lynch. He's here.
All right, get him up on stage
and I'll tell everybody
he's on his way. Okay.
Mr. Brava, I'm afraid
we need to hurry.
Mr. Brava, no advance
copy of your speech
has been released. Why the secrecy?
Well, come hear it,
and you'll know.
Can you tell us anything about
what you're going to say?
You want a sound bite? Fine.
People who traffic in
humans are like cockroaches
hiding in the dark.
You have to expose
'em to the light.
What do you mean, "expose"?
Will you be naming somebody?
Meet me through the
staff door, Carmen
Mr. Brava.
Wait here. Uh, Mr. Brava.
I'll be right back. Mr. Brava!
That was Hector Brava,
the keynote speaker
for the Human Global Conference.
Mr. Brava?
We really have to...
Help me! Somebody, please!
Andy Burnside-
Kane County Sheriff.
Agent Teresa Lisbon.
This is Patrick Jane, our consultant.
- Hi.
So the victim's name
was Hector Brava.
He was a do-gooder.
Ran an organization called the
Sheltering Light Foundation.
They fight human trafficking.
There's a conference going on.
He was supposed to give
some kind of a speech.
So you're the psychic, huh?
- No.
-  No such thing as psychics.
All right. Thanks.
Looks like cause of death
is blunt force trauma
to the back of the head.
Yeah, some of my men
found a fire extinguisher
with blood on it over there.
No, uh, usable
prints on it, though.
If he was here to make a speech,
what was he doing back here?
This.
It's a text message.
"Meet me through the
staff door. Carmen."
Tracking the sender now.
How many Carmens have you I.
D.'d at the hotel?
Two employees at the hotel,
another two were
attending the conference.
They all have alibis, though.
We're gonna keep looking.
He had his wallet on him,
all his credit cards,
a lot of money,
so you can rule robbery out.
Maybe. Where's his speech?
Hmm?
Well, you just said Brava was
on the way to deliver a speech.
Wouldn't he have that speech on
his person, or notes at least?
Did you find anything? No.
Find out everything you
can about the speech.
You got it.
What?
Uh, there's a contradiction here.
The murder itself
feels improvised--
the fire extinguisher,
the semipublic location.
But the setup...
The text message was planned.
No robbery to speak of.
No assault other than
the blow to the head.
It doesn't feel like
an anger killing.
It feels more like an
act of desperation.
The murderer wanted to keep
Brava from doing something
or saying something.
That's just what our psychic said.
Your psychic? Kristina Frye.
You're kidding.
What, you've heard of her?
Relax.
Don't force the memory.
It'll come, and the
details will emerge.
How much you paying her, Sheriff?
That's none of your business.
Oh, that much? I'm working
for the wrong people.
Ms. Frye, hi.
It's nice to see you again.
You, too. Thank you.
We'll talk later.
So you got the Sheriff
wrapped around your finger.
Sheriff Burnside is a man
with an admirably open mind.
Mm, yes. He's also a man that
likes to watch television
with a cat curled
up asleep on his lap
while his mother sits
next to him and knits.
But I'm sure he'd prefer
that to remain a secret.
Well, I thought you said
you weren't psychic.
Oh, he is. He's just
not ready to accept it.
Actually, it was the
cat hair on your pants,
lack of wedding ring and your
general live-with-mom vibe.
But if you want to believe
that his dead Uncle Harry
came down and whispered it in my ear,
then be my guest.
Don't you ever get tired
of your own cynicism?
Oh, weary as hell.
What's the alternative?
Why don't we give them a
little bit of time to catch up?
Sorry about the mom thing.
♫ The Mentalist 2x22 ♫
Red Letter
Original air date on May 13, 2010
-- sync, corrected by elderman
-- for www.Addic7ed.Com --
I have a question.
What are you doing
working with the cops?
I thought you were a
spiritual psychoanalyst.
Did your patients catch on to you?
I still have my practice.
Why, you looking for a therapist?
Uh, let me think about that.
No. I heard that
psychoanalysts are a disease
that present themselves as a cure.
And on top of that,
you add in ghosts.
Reflexive mockery-
-a sign of a troubled soul, Patrick.
You got bored, didn't you?
Got too easy taking their money.
No. I think our gift obliges
us to help other people.
Oh, is that what you think?
Mm-hmm. Our gift gives
us an obligation to help.
I like that line. I'm gonna use it.
Van Pelt says there's
a problem tracing
the text message
that Brava got. What?
Well, the trail leads to
an electronic dead drop.
No way to trace it back.
But she's gonna look at his other phones,
run down those calls.
And what about the speech?
There's no word yet on whether
he had it on him or not.
But we haven't talked to
the wife yet. She's inside.
Hector and I knew something
like this might happen.
He always said there was too much
at stake to waste time worrying.
What were you and your
husband worried about?
The traffickers--
people who profit from the
enslavement of others.
Hector was tireless in
his pursuit of them.
Is there anyone you can think of
who may have wanted to kill him?
Agent, my husband's received
half a dozen death threats
since Christmas.
If you're asking for names,
well, we didn't make a
habit of filing the notes.
He was gonna give a speech today.
Did he have it on him?
Yes. Why?
Well, there was some
secrecy surrounding it.
Uh, do--do you know hat
he was gonna talk about?
No, I didn't.
That wasn't unusual.
Hector rarely shared the
details of his work with me.
It was his way of protecting me.
The person you need to
talk to is Russell Bigelow.
He did research for Hector.
Ilsa, um...
You've been told who
I am and what I do?
Uh, yes.
My communication with
the other side is like
a long-distance phone call
with a bad connection.
So often the messages I
receive are meaningless to me,
but not to those with ones
who've passed over, okay?
I'm really not big on this,
um, supernatural stuff.
You're not alone.
Your husband wants me to
remind you of something--
something that will make
you smile. It's, uh...
I'm getting an image of,
um... cherry blossoms?
Does that mean anything to you?
Yes. Uh...
We were married
under a cherry tree.
How could you know that?
He can recall foliage
from his wedding day,
but he can't tell
you who killed him?
Crossing over to the other
side can be confusing.
It's a bit like waking
up from anesthesia.
Sometimes it can take a
while to get real clarity.
Huh. Oh, well, makes sense.
Does the name Carmen
mean anything to you?
Uh, the opera. Why?
That's pretty. Uh, my turn.
Ilsa... did your husband
ever cheat on you?
Did you cheat on him?
Why would you ask that?
You--you're very Noble and-
-and dignified.
Very stoic.
A Jackie O. thing going on there.
Uh, maybe you don't give a crap.
Maybe you're happy he's dead.
Maybe not.
I'd like you to leave now.
Good idea. Jane, enough fun.
Let's go.
Yeah.
Thank you for the tea. Very tasty.
Come on.
Nice work.
She was hiding something.
I wanted to see what it was.
And what'd you learn?
Well, it's early days.
She's got a good arm.
Did learn that.
I'm--I'm not so sure
this is such a good idea
I talk about this stuff.
I-I-I'm just a researcher,
you know? I... listen, Mr. Bigelow,
we understand that
you're frightened,
but we really need to know
what was in that speech.
You don't understand.
Look, trafficking generates billions.
I mean, there are governments
behind this stuff.
It's like these people
can get to anybody.
I mean, Hector's death
already proves that.
Then we can offer you
protection, Russell.
But only if you tell
us what you know.
If you don't help us,
then all the work
that you've done to stop these
guys will be for nothing.
Traffickers use
quasi-legit businesses
to launder their money
around the world.
I watch audit trails.
We made a connection.
That's what's in Hector's speech.
What connection?
Have you ever heard of the world
anti-trafficking coalition?
One of the backers of
the conference, right?
Yeah. A major charity.
It's run by a guy named
Christopher Lynch.
They assisted us in shutting
down a bunch of networks,
but the trafficking continued.
The money just went someplace else.
So it took a while to trace it,
but we found out
the coalition is a front
for a trafficking group.
You know, they used us to shut
down their own competition,
building themselves a monopoly.
Here.
That the speech? My copy.
And why didn't you
notify the authorities
once you figured out
what was going on?
'Cause Hector said that he
wanted to denounce Lynch himself,
in public.
I said it was too dangerous,
but he just wouldn't listen.
Did Brava ever mention
anybody named Carmen to you?
No. No, not to me.
Why?
So Bigelow is saying
that the people
fighting human trafficking
were traffickers. Apparently.
All right. You and Cho
go talk to this Lynch.
- See what he has to say for himself.
- Okay, you got it.
Are you guys joking?
Because your humor's in bad taste.
Hector was a close colleague
and a good friend.
Who was planning to give a
speech that would identify
your coalition as a front
for human traffickers,
Mr. Lynch. He named
you specifically.
Look, someone is leading you
down the garden path, gentlemen.
Okay, there's no basis
of truth in this.
Surely you can see that it's
in the traffickers' interest
to split us up,
get us suspecting each other.
Looks like Brava went
past suspecting you.
Oh, please. Hector saw
conspiracies everywhere.
You know, he liked
being in the spotlight.
We read the speech.
It makes a pretty convincing case.
Okay, look. We're gonna
clear this up right now.
I will have my lawyers give
you access to all our records,
and then you will see that the
coalition has nothing to hide.
Does the name "Carmen"
mean anything to you?
No. Can you think of anybody
who'd want to kill Brava?
Oh, yeah, maybe only
a few hundred people.
I ju--uh, wait a second.
One thing.
Second night of the convention,
I saw Hector having an argument
with a man named Tariq Sharif
outside the hotel bar,
and for my money,
the argument was about a woman.
How could you tell?
Because I know these guys,
and they definitely weren't
having a discussion
about immigration policy.
How's it coming with Lynch?
Says a man called Tariq Sharif
was fighting with Brava.
I'm checking for an I.D.
on Sharif right now.
I took a look at the records that
Lynch's lawyer e-mailed over.
First glance, couldn't
find anything that supports
Brava's accusations.
I checked Lynch's phone records.
He made a single call
right after we left
the interview to an
anonymous disposable cell.
Does it say where it originated?
Here's the weird thing...
The call ends at a cell tower
out in the middle of nowhere.
That is weird. Right? So we figured
maybe we'd go check it out.
All right.
Here we go. I got him.
Here's Tariq Sharif.
♪
I'll see if anybody's seen Sharif.
Excuse me.
Have you seen him?
He's about 6'2",
gray hair, mustache?
He's by the pool. Okay.
♪
- What are you doing?
- Nothing.
Mr. Sharif?
Yes?
We're with the CBI.
Agent Lisbon. Mr. Jane.
Won't you sit down?
Well, don't mind if we do.
I was just telling Mr.
Sharif that his spirit is troubled.
There's a wrong that
he burns to rectify.
Mm, interesting.
Hector was an old friend.
I, uh, pushed him
to take up the trafficking problem.
Naturally, I feel responsible.
They're great glasses.
Yeah. Could--could I try those?
Uh, no. Okay.
Mr. Sharif, why don't you
take off the sunglasses?
Now.
Oh!
You got a... owie.
It was a misunderstanding.
He was drunk.
It didn't have anything to
do with Ilsa, by any chance?
- It was nothing like that.
- It was exactly like that.
You have a strong connection
with Ilsa--a bond.
See?
Ilsa and I were very close.
Uh...
By chance, we found ourselves
here alone on the first night.
I expressed my deep
admiration for her.
She returned my feelings but
was afraid to act on it.
Hector found out.
Hypocrite that he is,
he attacked me.
How is he a hypocrite?
Because he was unfaithful to her.
Mm. I did say.
You did.
Mr. Sharif, you were saying that Mr.
Brava was unfaithful?
I'm a pacifist, not a coward.
You don't strike me
without repercussions.
I went to his suite the night
before he died to confront him.
A woman was leaving.
It wasn't Ilsa.
Was it someone from the conference?
It wasn't that kind of woman.
She was young, pretty,
uh, cheap clothes.
I assume she was a
prostitute. Carmen.
'Keep out'
Far as I can tell,
this is the only structure
within a half mile
of the cell tower
Lynch's call stopped at.
- Well, I don't see anything.
- Nope. Not a thing.
Think they have dogs?
Probably.
Hey, listen.
There.
You have misread the
situation, agents.
I am entirely ignorant
of whatever it is
that you are accusing me of.
You're lying.
We've got the phone records.
You called your goons and told 'em
to lock those women up so
your guys could escape.
I'm sorry. Goons? What goons?
And records can be faked.
No, those women in the truck-
-that was you.
Hector Brava-- that was you, too.
You're wrong.
I weep for those
poor souls you found.
And as I said,
Hector was a dear friend.
What about Carmen?
Who's Carmen?
And where's my lawyer?
Tough.
Sociopath. Wolf among the sheep.
He's a caught wolf now.
Phone call's enough to connect him
to about 20 different
felony charges,
not even counting the homicide.
He's going away for a long time.
- She likes you, that one.
- Which one?
- The blonde one.
- What?
And you like her.
Wha--I'm not so sure I
know where this is headed.
You know exactly
where this is headed.
Do you ever consider dating again?
Do you?
How did we get to
this point so quickly?
I'm just saying,
I think it would be a good thing.
What would?
Uh, charging Lynch
with Brava's murder.
How close are we?
A confession would help.
Well, why don't you ask
one of her spirits?
I'm sure they'll provide
the evidence that's needed.
Where are you going?
This case is solving
itself without me.
I have errands to run.
Lisbon.
Yeah.
Christopher Lynch
didn't kill Brava.
No. The emotion he was trying
to conceal was contempt.
Lynch didn't consider
him worth killing.
A deeply evil man, but not
one who committed this crime.
Mm.
Thank you.
What if I didn't say "spirits"?
What if I said "instincts"?
Would that be something
you could accept?
Oh, well, maybe.
'Cause they're telling
me to come with you.
Are they? Why?
'Cause the last time you
spoke with Ilsa Engels,
she threw a teacup at your head.
It was a saucer.
It wasn't a teacup.
And who said I'm going
to see Ilsa Engels?
Tell me that you're not.
She thinks well of me.
I can communicate with her husband.
And she'll only talk
to you if I'm there.
Well, I guess I have no choice
but to bring you along with me.
You think you manipulated me
into coming with you, don't you?
No, I don't. I think you
manipulated me into thinking
I manipulated you
into coming with me.
Okay, I'm just gonna come straight out,
and I'm gonna say
I'm sorry for the, uh,
obnoxious infidelity remarks earlier,
and I humbly beg your forgiveness.
Mm.
Sorry.
Would you mind talking to us a
little bit about Tariq Sharif?
He was drunk. He said things
he shouldn't have said,
and I excused myself
from his company.
And then your husband
punched him in the face.
I didn't tell Hector to hit him,
if that's what you're asking.
I won't pretend I'm particularly
sad that Hector punched him.
He said things that he--
he acted like a pig and an ass.
A pig and an ass?
That can't be good.
We need to ask you again about
the night before Hector died.
I, um...
I had a department meeting.
I stayed up in Berkeley.
And, um, is there any chance
that a woman could've been
visiting with Hector that night?
If Tariq said that, he's lying.
He wouldn't dare say that
if Hector was still alive.
It's disgusting.
Disgusting.
Um, well, I-I guess I should go.
Okay. Well,
I still have some business
to attend to here, so, uh...
Yeah, I'm gonna catch
a cab out front.
Okay.
Oh, nice call on the
cherry blossoms,
by the way. How so?
The wedding photograph-
March '97, D.C.
March through to April
is the annual Cerry
Blossom Festival in D.C.
Patrick, you credit me
with far too much cunning.
You're very good. Very compelling.
Thank you.
I'll see you later.
Bye.
Lisbon.
Meet me at the hotel bar.
Cheers. Oh, sweetheart,
there you are. Join us.
Uh, I've got us a room,
and our friend here...
Novella.
Novella. She's gonna help
us explore some boundaries.
No, she's not.
Work with me, Teresa.
You're pretty, uh,
well, you're pretty
adventurous, right?
Because my--my lady,
she--she gets a little
out there at times.
Gettin' there now.
Let's go upstairs and see.
You just have to work
things out with Howie.
Okay. Barkeep!
How can I help you?
Another bottle of the good stuff?
Uh, no, thanks.
Uh... you're the pimp?
Hey. Not nice.
Well, business manager, then.
Concerned friend.
Whatever. We'd like to take
our little soiree upstairs
to a more private location.
Novella says that we
have to talk to you.
If it's gonna be the two of you,
it's gonna be extra.
Sure. She's paying.
I should probably tell
you that I am Agent
for the California
Bureau of Investigation.
Oh, wow.
She has a gun, too. And handcuffs.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
This is entrapment. I want a lawyer.
What you want is to take
a look at this picture
and tell me if you
recognize this man.
Nope. Never seen him.
But that guy-- him I recognize.
He was in here getting a
girl just the other night.
No. No way.
Look, I might not be Denzel,
but I do okay.
Besides, I couldn't afford
a prostitute on my salary,
believe me. Not for you.
For your boss, Brava.
Is that something
you did a lot of--
procuring women for him?
Wow. The man's dead.
Are you seriously gonna drag his
name through the mud like this?
I'm not looking to destroy
anybody's reputation, Russell.
I just need to know what happened.
Ilsa was back in Berkeley.
He called me and said he
needed me to do him a favor.
He couldn't go down
to the bar himself,
because somebody
would recognize him.
Somebody could've recognized you.
Nobody did.
I was lucky.
It was hard for you.
Sure.
Sure, it would've been easier
if he didn't do it at all,
but...
Look, a-all I could do was just
keep him from getting caught.
Is there anything you can
tell us about the girl?
Uh... I think her
name was... Claret.
Claret. It's French.
What did Brava mean when he said
he wanted to make it regular?
Well, I mean, not, like,
actually regular,
because he died and all,
but every Thursday afternoon,
it was gonna be.
He had a place up in Oakland,
he told me.
Do you have an address?
Sure. And a key, too.
- I think it's this one on the left.
- Yeah.
So would you ever, uh...
You know...
Pay for sex? No.
Yeah. It's weird, right?
Weird? No. Expensive.
Hey.
Check this out.
"Carmen."
Bingo.
What do you got?
Well, we tracked
Carmen's phone number.
It's an apartment rented
to a Sally Alvarez.
So "Carmen" was just a
name she used for work?
Mm. Alvarez has been picked up
a couple times for soliciting,
once for possession.
She skipped on that
apartment about a month ago,
but her P.O. gave us an address
that was good as of last week.
Call Burnside. Tell him
we're gonna pick her up.
Hey, boss. There was a
Carmen Reyes who called Brava
on his hotel phone twice
the night before he died.
Left her name on the
hotel messaging system.
There's no record of Sally Alvarez
calling the hotel-- home or cell.
Where did the call originate from?
Sunset Horizon Motor
Court in San Desidera.
A Carmen Reyes checked
in two days ago.
She's still there. All right.
Then we've got two locations
to look for her at.
Or we have two Carmens.
Two Carmens?
Two Carmens. What does
that mean, two Carmens?
Well, it means things
are getting interesting.
Ah, well, as long as
it's interesting for you.
I'll go with Van Pelt.
There's just something
about motels--
old-fashioned and illicit,
both at the same time.
Is that an invitation?
Whoa. Well, look at you,
just showing up like a bad Penny.
I had a premonition you'd be here.
Really?
No. Lisbon told me.
Upstairs. 204.
Grace, you know Kristina? Yeah.
Hi. Hi.
Did your psychic powers
tell you to come?
I did have an instinct
you were about to get
a break in this case.
Oh, I think you might have just
made Agent Van Pelt's day.
We're looking for Carmen Reyes.
Actually, we have two
addresses for her.
This is just one of 'em.
Her real name is Sally Alvarez.
Wait a second. Sally Alvarez.
I know that name.
She communicated with
me a short time ago.
She's passed over.
I'm pretty sure she's
still in there.
Sally?
Open it up.
Step back, sir. Oh.
She's down.
Hey, Cho. We found Sally Alvarez.
She's been dead for
about six hours.
Blunt force trauma to the head.
She's dead? Oh, my God.
That's amazing.
Why? Kristina Frye said Sally
passed over. She predicted it.
She did? Yes.
Can I have that? Thank you.
Cho, please do not believe
this mystic mumbo jumbo.
Gullible Grace buried the lead.
I was right. There were
two Carmens. There were?
That's right, and we have
the real one right here.
Carmen Reyes.
She claims to be Hector
Brava's daughter.
A year ago, my mother was
diagnosed with cancer.
Uh, it got bad very fast.
She was gone in less than a month.
Before she died, she told me
Hector Brava was my father.
And after the funeral,
I wrote to him.
I never heard back.
I thought maybe he'd forgotten her.
I wrote there was nothing
I wanted from him,
only to meet the man
who was my father.
He still didn't answer?
I saw somewhere that he was
delivering a speech here.
I thought I'd go confront him.
You were angry.
I wanted to talk to him.
Did you?
When?
The morning he died?
The night before.
I went to his suite.
What happened?
He let me in.
He was friendly,
until I told him I
was his daughter.
He got very upset and angry.
He said, I could not
be his daughter.
He said, he already
met his daughter,
and what kind of scam
was I trying to play?
He turned so pale
and shook all over.
He threw me out of the
room and locked the door,
so I left.
And that was last time you saw him?
On the news, it said what happened.
I didn't know what to do.
And what about the text message?
Did you send that?
I don't have a phone.
So is she telling the truth?
I'm not sure.
Brava's spirit is
deeply conflicted.
I can't get a clear reading.
What are you using, dial-up?
My question is,
if she's telling the truth,
why was Sally Alvarez
pretending to be Carmen Reyes?
I talked to Bigelow.
He kept a record of all
work correspondences
but didn't have anything to do
with Brava's personal letters.
There's no way to know if
her story checks out or not.
If Brava's her father,
she's got motive.
She's not the only one.
I could never have children.
Is it true?
Is she really Hector's daughter?
We don't know, ma'am.
She's agreed to take
a paternity test.
I think she might be
telling the truth.
So you think she might be
the one that killed Hector.
Well, maybe... and
then maybe it was you.
I have to say, ma'am,
I-it's pretty hard to believe
that you didn't know
about his behavior.
Yes, I knew. Hector was a
passionate and heroic man
who devoted himself
to helping others.
His flaws were
correspondingly oversized.
And his behavior was okay with you?
I accepted it.
The good in him outweighed the bad.
If he'd told me, maybe I could've
done something to prevent it.
Maybe I could've saved him.
What for?
How could you not want to get
away from his serial philandering,
from the prison of your loveless
marriage? That's not true!
I loved my husband,
and he loved me!
Well, maybe we can get
in contact with him now.
You could do that, couldn't you?
It would certainly
clear up a few things.
Would you do that?
Would you talk to my husband?
Yes, Ilsa.
What are you doing?
What does it look like I'm doing?
Okay, so Van Pelt
is bringing Carmen.
Rigsby's gonna bring
Richard Bigelow.
Cho is gonna pick up
Tariq Sharif and Stacey.
So we're all set.
What's all set for what?
We're all set for,
uh, Kristina Frye
to contact Hector Brava's spirit.
I need everybody connected
with his passing.
Okay. Well, uh, I guess...
Now listen, just make sure
Brava's spirit has a
thirst for revenge.
He wants to put some kind
of a curse on the killer,
you know what I mean?
That kind of thing.
And then I'll take it from there.
I can't do that.
Yes, you can.
It is a necessary lie.
I can only contact Hector Brava's
spirit and speak as he wants me to.
To do otherwise would
be to abuse my gift.
Everything okay?
Yep. Everything's good.
It's perfect.
Are we starting now?
Almost.
I'll just get the door.
Welcome.
Come on in.
Thanks for coming.
It was your husband's request.
Your husband's daughter.
Well, thank you all for coming.
Patrick will be assisting me.
So in order for this to work,
I need everybody to
be calm and focused.
I want you to look at the candle
in the center of the table.
Focus on the flame and
concentrate on Hector.
Now... he's here.
I can feel him.
Hector...
Who do you wish to speak to?
The killer's here.
Know this--
Hector Brava says...
vengeance will come.
Your blood will spill...
before the rising sun.
Ohh. I sense him.
I-I can almost see an image.
I-I-it's hazy.
Oh, it...
Ohh, it's as if it could just--
Hector. Hector, wait.
Stop. Don't go.
Show us who the killer is.
There it is.
A door.
"Employees only."
And an empty hallway.
Footsteps... close...
Close...
Aah! Ugh! Oh!
I see you.
I'm sorry.
Man, you scared me
to death with that.
Whew. It's okay.
You can relax, Bigelow.
It's over. I know it
was you that did it.
What, because I got frantic
and fell out of my chair?
Because you managed
Brava's correspondence,
you were the first one to
read Carmen's letters, yes?
You set Brava up on
a date with Sally
and had her pretend to be Carmen,
and then you told Brava
that he had sex with
his own daughter. Lord.
And then the real deal showed up,
so you faked Carmen's message,
and when Brava walked through
that service door, you killed him.
And you killed poor Sally
Alvarez to cover your tracks.
Mm-hmm.
And now you'll pay for
the crime you committed.
Your blood will spill
before the sun rises.
That part I'm not so sure about.
It came in the mail.
Just out of the blue. Just a...
letter describing an affair
Brava had 20 years ago,
naming the woman and the place.
And that came from Carmen Reyes.
The real Carmen.
That gave you all the facts you needed-
things about the affair
that only Brava and
Carmen's mother would know.
Right? Yeah.
So why'd you do it?
Why put a man through
that kind of suffering?
Was it the money?
Or did you just like
having Brava in your power?
Do you know I've been running
numbers on trafficking for Brava
and setting him up on his dates for,
like, five years?
And do you think that he ever,
ever thanked me?
Said, "I'm sorry"?
Said, "I'm gonna make this
up to you one day, Russell"?
I knew Sally from a whorehouse
up in Northern California.
I told her if she
pretended to be Carmen,
we could blackmail Brava
and split the money.
The letter just gave
us everything we needed
to make Brava think that
she was the real deal.
And he was not one for asking a
whole lot of questions, so...
Then the real Carmen showed up.
Yeah.
He called me as soon
as she left his room,
freaked. So I played dumb.
But then the next morning,
he called me
and he said, "we need to talk."
It was pretty clear
he figured it out.
And so you went to the hotel
and texted Brava from
the service hallway.
I just--I just wanted
to keep him quiet.
And Sally Alvarez? You had to
keep her quiet, too, right?
You know, I was a
really good researcher.
I bet.
Come on.
Agent Van Pelt,
you wanted to see me?
Oh, yeah. Hi, Carmen.
I just wanted to go over a
few things in your statement.
Let's go in the kitchen.
So...
Nice working with you.
Yeah.
Yeah, you were very
good back there.
Uh, you almost had
me with the whole
"I can't misuse my gift for
fear of what might happen" bit.
I did what I said I would.
I spoke the words the spirits
told me to speak, nothing more.
Really?
Don't you know me by now?
Don't you know I wouldn't
lie about a thing like that?
Ms. Frye, thank you so much.
We couldn't have closed this one
without you. Well, that's debatable.
You're welcome.
Although I have to say it looks
like the spirits got it wrong.
I guess being dead doesn't
make you infallible.
Well, what do you mean?
The killer was caught,
and justice was served.
Sure. But no blood was spilled.
Look, he's right there.
Hey! Hey, hey! Murderer!
Oh, come on.
That was pure luck.
Admit it.
If you say so.
Oh, I know so.
The dead are dead.
You can't talk to them.
And yet I do.
Yeah...
You're very good.
I go this way.
Okay. It was nice seeing you again.
You, too.
Bye.
Kristina? Yes.
That's with a "K," right?
Yes.
You wanna go get a coffee?
I'll drink tea myself,
but you can drink as
much coffee as you want.
Yeah, I'd like that.
I can't right now, though.
I-I have to be somewhere else.
Uh, maybe some other time?
Some other time.
Sorry, not "maybe." Definitely.
Sometime soon.
Call me.
-- sync, corrected by elderman --
-- for www.Addic7ed.Com --
www.tvsubtitles.net