****
Are you mr.Black?
Yeah.
You scared me.
So... I just...
Tell me why i'm here.
I have something i need done.
So do most women.You're gonna
have to be more specific.
Right.Yes.Sorry.
Um,what i need... I don't
know quite how to put it.
Well,you're just gonna
have to open your mouth
And say it out loud in full detail,Like
you're talking to your priest.
You show me yours.I'll show
you mine.That's how it works.
Okay.
Here.
I want you to kill him.
How much do you charge?
-=http://bbs.sfileydy.com=-
Proudly Presents
Sync:Çm3P
The Mentalist
Season 2 Episode 19
****
We think she was killed
about an hour ago.
Neighbor heard screaming,called 9-1.
Anybody see anything?
We've got sac p.d.canvassing,but so
far nothing-- Just an average night.
Average night,average
neighborhood,Average murder.
Why are we here?
Because the victim is assistant
district attorney kelly flower.
- You worked with her.
- Yeah,we all did.
Kelly was good people.
Forensics found a
casing.Said it was 9-mil.
Almost point-blank,judging
from the stippling.
Deputy coroner said no sexual assault,But
her nightgown's ripped and tangled.
She was crawling in it.
Remodel?
Kelly's one of us.
Hightower's already
approved the overtime.
You know the drill.
Why is that the drill?
I mean,for everyone else,It just
looks like for your own,you try harder.
We do.
It's a deterrent.
It sends out a message--nobody gets
away with killing a cop,A judge or a d.a.
cho can get a list of kelly's cases,
See who she put away that held a grudge.
It's not a deterrent.It's
revenge,really.
I mean,and that's not a
criticism,'Cause i'm all about revenge.
I mean,revenge can be very productive.
- Productive?
- Well,take rigsby.
Van pelt breaks up with him.Now
he's in the best shape of his life.
I mean,he's hitting the
gym,what,six times a week?
Look at him.
He is brimming with sexual confidence.
Jane,cut it out.
Not on my account.It's fine.
See?Fine.My point--there is
nothing wrong with revenge.
Van pelt,any damage to the
windows or the back door?
No,nothing.
No sign of forced entry,so
either she let him in,or...
Husband's here.
He let himself in.
Oh,my god!No!Kelly,no!No!No!God,no!
Tiffany wants you to call her back.
Oh,thanks.
Said to tell you you're a very bad boy.
Did she?
- Agent hightower,hi.
- Morning.
You two know marc odenthal
from the d.a.'s office?
Sure.
We're gonna talk with
the district attorney.
What can you tell me about kelly's case?
We're looking at anybody who had
access to the house Cbs From work,
the neighborhood,the
local dog park,anywhere.
Husband?
Flower was too upset to talk last
night.Jane and i are heading over there now.
And we've got a list of past defendants.
At least four have expressed
written or verbal threats.
The d.a.told me to give you this.
It includes her current cases.
Hang on.Hank draber.The smuggler?
Smuggling drugs,conspiracy to murder.
We haven't been able to
lay a glove on 'em before.
Draber's trial was
supposed to start next week.
I just got judge hildred
to grant a continuance.
It's gonna take me three
months just to learn the file.
Go.Take van pelt.
****
All right.There he is.Mr.Draber!
What do you want?
So how are you getting
along lately?Any problems?
You... My wife is dead,and
you're wasting your time on me?
Mr.Flower,I knew your wife.
Now we're gonna find out who
did this,even if it's you.
You understand?
So how were you two getting along?
We loved each other.
Everything was good.
How was the remodel?That
can be stressful.
Things were good.
But that day,we fought.
That's why i went to the
movies-- Over her hours.
It... It was just so stupid.
She was so stressed over
that draber case,you know?
She called it her "career-maker."
That's what she said-- "career-maker."
So you argued.Did it turn physical?
No.I loved her.
I would never do
anything like that.Never.
Mr.Flower?I got the tarp on the roof In
case it rains before you want me back.
Didn't mean to interrupt.I'll
get out of your hair now.
Thank you.That's our
contractor cale sylvan.He's,uh--
- patrick jane.How you doing?
- Good.
You're standing in the...
Can i ask yoru a question?
Uh,would you recommend A flash hot
water heater over a regular one?
I mean,i was leaning towards
flash,But they're very expensive.
Well,you know,flash will pay for
itself in energy savings Pretty quick,
but it depends on consumption.
Of course.That's a very good point.
Um,do you have a card?
- Sure.
- Great.
- I'll maybe give you a call.
Well,thanks for your time,mr.Flower.
Thank you.
Cale sylvan is a dangerous
psychopath,And he killed kelly flower.
How's that?
- He had access,and he looked evil.
- And...
When i told him he was standing
in her blood,What was his reaction?
Not horror.Not embarrassment.
No emotion at all.All
right.I'll run him.
Excellent.Having prints might help,no?
You know,you guys should be more
careful.You almost got yourselves shot.
It's a good thing you look like cops.
We could take you in,but you'll lawyer
up,And we'll all waste a lot of time.
But here we can have a
nice conversation,right?
Yeah.That sounds reasonable.
Fine.
Kelly flower was all set to fry your ass
in court.You were looking at 20 years,easy.
Now the trial's been
postponed who knows how long.
That gives you motive for her murder.
That one's a winner.I know it is.
Here you go.You like the lotto,huh?
- None of your business.
- Mom.come on.
You have pretty hair.
My mom's a little senile.
Now who'd take care of your mother
If kelly flower put you in jail?
You know,killing a prosecutor is--is
almost as bad As killing a cop,right?
It's not something i want
to get my hands dirty with.
I got enough problems
as it is.Right,mom?
Close your mouth,muffin.
Well,jane's right.
Sylvan is a killer.
You know,it feels good to be right.
Prints brought up these
i.d.s.We got carl sennett,
A witness in an accidental
drowning in arizona,
Cory sampson,who lived next door
To a hit-and-run victim in seattle,
And chad sewell,wanted for questioning
About the murder of his boss,
a bank executive in reno.
We have four other deaths that
sylvan's linked to In some other way.
He's not just a
killer.He's a serial killer.
Well,saddle up.Lock and load.Do
what you do.Go--go bring him in.
We can't.
- Nope.
- What?
All we have is that cale sylvan
liked to change his name--
Not illegal--and that
bad luck followed him.
We don't even have enough
for a search warrant.
He'll kill again.You--
you know what he is,lisbon.
Knowing isn't proving.
Rigsby,have cho set up On sylvan's
house 24-hour surveillance.
If he shows up,have cho follow
him.Maybe we'll get lucky.
Okay.
This--this
is ridiculous.
- I... I know.
- I'm gonna go with cho.
Go.
Sylvan's smart enough
to know we'll be here.
He won't be coming back.
It's a waste of time.
What are you reading there,cho?
"wuthering heights."
Well,i'm gonna take a stroll.
Let me know how it ends.
Not well.
Cho said jane ditched him at
sylvan's.Have you seen him?
Nope.There's something hinky here,boss.
These are photos of some of
the victims linked to sylvan.
Different ages,sexes,races.
Exactly.A serial killer almost
always hunts the same kind of prey.
This doesn't make sense
as a serial killer's m.o.
it does when you look
at sylvan's financials.
I tracked bank records for
all the i.d.s we could find.
Sylvan received substantial payments
Just before and just after each death.
He kills for money?He's a hit man?
A psychopath who made money
from his hobby.It's outstanding.
You do something you love.You never
have to work a day in your life.
Where the hell have you been?
Me?Oh,i've been around.
I found a web site registered
to one of his old identies.
It says to "call mr.Black
for odd josbs of any sort."
Well,i guess we should give him a call.
Grace,do you happen to have any
photographs Of,uh,you know,ex-boyfriends?
I want you to kill him.
How much do you charge?
Ask him again,grace.You're a busy
lady.You don't have all night.
You gonna answer me or not?I
want the bastard dead--soon.
- She's convincing.
- Trying to work here.
Okay.
I charge $50,000.
And what you're asking is pretty easy.
I mean,you just gotta have To
stop thinking of him as a person.
The rest is just a physics
problem--gravity,force,torque.
Ask for proof of what he does.
Torque is well and good,But i
need to know that you're for real.
See,maybe you're a hitter.
Maybe you're a cop.
- Long shot.
- Trying to work here.
Let me show you somethin'.
How's that?
- Let's move.
- No,no,no.It's a test.
Grace,listen.Listen very carefully.
Are you a cop?
I'm not a cop.
I'm just careful,like you.
I just want to know that
i have the right man.
Besides,don't you want to show me...
Besides,Don't you want to show
me,So you can make me afraid?
That's what you like,isn't
it-- Seeing the fear?
You show me yours,and
i'll show you mine.
I have something to show you then.
Just watch for a second.
Oh,wait.Oh,please!
Look at it.
It's my last job.
The client was very happy.
Proof.That's proof.Proof.
- Are we gonna do business?
- Yes,we are.
- Cbi!Drop the knife!
- Don't move!
- Hands on your head!
- Drop the knife now!
Don't move!On your knees!
Cale sylvan,you're under arrest
for the murder of kelly flower.
Hands on your head!
Jane,you can come out.
okay.
How'd you know he had proof?
Well,he's a narcissist.Needs
affirmation,trophies.
Who paid you to kill kelly?
Tell 'em.You'll feel better.
I would like to talk to my lawyer.
And i'll see you clowns in court.
****
Catching killers i enjoy,But being
reminded that we're just a cog In a petty,
fascist machine,that
is a little depressing.
Crime-fighting is hard.Suck it up.
If you weren't on the witness list,
I wouldn't even let you In the
same time zone as judge dread.
"judge dread"--can't possibly
be as much fun as it sounds.
Oh,please!Please!What do you want?
Oh,god!Oh,god,don't hurt me!
Oh,god!Oh,god,don't!
Please!Please!
Your honor,i object.
This video is inflammatory
and prejudicial.
Although we'll stipulate to the
fact That kelly flower was murdered,
we reserve our right to deny That there is
probable cause my client committed said murder.
And we also object to the
chain of custody for this video.
Is that even a sentence?
Quiet in the gallery!
You say another word,and
you'll regret it.
Well,i'm...i'm sorry,your honor,but this woman
Is spouting nothing but ludicrous pettifoggery,
And,uh,i'm a little hungry.
Your honor,if you'll let
me down,i can handle him.
Mr.Jane-- that is
your name,correct?
That's correct.Patrick jane.
Well,this court hereby fines you $1,000.
make it $2,000,And let me tell
this,uh,tiresome woman to move it along.
- $2,000 then.
- Okay.
Counselor,you heard
the man.Move it along.
So,agent lisbon,Let's
get back to this video.
That night was the first
time you'd ever seen it?
- Yes.
- Are you sure?
Objection.Asked and answered.
I'll move on,your honor.
So you never entered Mr.Sylvan's
apartment and looked at the video
On his computer or instructed
anyone else to do so?
No.
Well,then i need you to
answer a puzzling question.
Your honor,i would like to enter this
into evidence As defense exhibit one.
I got this mug from mr.Sylvan's sink.
But he didn't put it there.
So...
So tell me,how is it that this mug
Has mr.Jane's fingerprints on it?
Agent lisbon,Did your consultant break
into mr.Sylvan's home Without a warrant?
No.No,of course not.
Your honor,may i have a moment
to confer with agent lisbon?
You make it quick.This
is getting interesting.
Bailiff.
That's how you knew sylvan had
proof.You'd already seen it.
i have no idea what
you're talking about.
Tell us what happenednow.
I was with cho.We were
staking out sylvan's place.
I decided i wanted to take a walk.
I happened upon sylvan's door,unlocked.
And like any concerned
citizen,I went in to look around
And checked that the
place hadn't been robbed.
Then i left.
- That's it.
- Oh,crap.
What's the story,mr.Odenthal?
Your honor... Mr.Jane did
enter mr.Sylvan's residence,
But only because he feared
there was an intruder inside.
You mean one besides himself?
I-it's not like i took
anything,your honor.
Your honor,what mr.Jane is trying to
say Is that he's not a state agent.
He's a private consultant.
Therefore,there's no
fourth amendment violation.
Mr.Jane is a charlatan who has made a mockery
Of our legal system on numerous occasions.
In fact,a few months ago
he refused to take a woman
To the hospital for poisoning
until she confessed to a murder.
She was not poisoned in the first
place,And it was just a very clever ruse--
- quiet,mr.Jane.
- For what it's worth.
You should be ashamed
of yourself anyway.
You,too,agent lisbon.You're the law.
I hold mr.Jane's search to be illegal,And any
evidence discovered then or during the sting
Is hereby excluded as
fruit of the poisonous tree.
The
video--out.
Any statements made by the
defendant To agent van pelt--out.
Your honor,i object.Your
anger is clouding your--
Mr.Odenthal,do you have any evidence of any
kind That yourconsultant hasn't crapped all over?
No,your honor.
Well,thenthe people v.Sylvan Is
hereby dismissed for lack of evidence.
Mr.Sylvan,you're free to go.
This is ridiculous,your honor.
This is wrong!
This don't make no sense!
I'll be seeingyou.
He killed my wife!
How can he go free?
Bailiff,bring in the next case.
I had a confession.I had
video.I had an airtight case.
And it's all out.
How could you break into his place?
Easy.The lock on the
back door was very flimsy.
Marc,i
apologize.I do.I--
also,i didn't think i'd be found out.
I mean,how was i to know they were
going to dust Formyfingerprints?
You let a killer back on the streets.
Actually,i got the
killer off the streets.
Keeping him off the
streets-- your job.
You're blaming me?
I'm not the one who got
the murder weapon tossed.
Court is theater.Whatever
side has the best liar wins.
Usually that's you,but
today she was better.
You're an arrogant little bastard.
Whoa,easy with the steel,brother.
Oh,relax.It's not loaded.
Look,marc,there is no
double jeopardy here.
We can still take this to trial.
I will find new evidence.I promise.
You're a menace.
When i'm d.a.,you'll never
work with this office again.
- So ambitious.
- Not your call,marc.
- Not then,not now.
- You're defending him?
- Thank you,lisbon.
- Shut up,jane.
I thought you two trusted each other.
- So did i.
- We do.
I--we
have trust.
I-i didn't tell her
because i didn't want her
To be complicit and then
have to lie about it later.
Some partnership you got going on here.
I'll have to send you home while the
professional standards unit Does its thing--
five days at least.
It's not her fault.
That will be the p.s.u.'s
determination,no doubt.
This is just the situation
we talked about,patrick.
Agent lisbon is responsible fov3r 11 5the
actions of her team members,Including you.
Yes,ma'am.
- Is that all?
- Yes.
Look,lisbon,i'm so sorry.I really am.
Jane.
Lisbon needs some time off.
A few days off will do her good.
Nice talking with you.
Rigsby,go back through
sylvan's financials.
Van pelt,take another look at
kelly's video of her murder.
See if we missed anything.
Hey,we'll serve up sylvan As
your welcome back present,okay?
It's a little chilly in here.
Do you want to go get a coffee?
Oh,come on.Look at the bright side.You get
five days off.You get five days off from me.
Cho,you're in charge.He's
your problem now.
That's good.Cho's a big boy.He
knows how to look after me.
You want to get a coffee?
Did you bring a book?
Could be a bit of a wait.
What are we doing here?
You're still mad with me
about lisbon's suspension.
Yeah.It's your fault.
You know,Sometimes in order to catch
these risk takers,We have to take risks.
There can be fallout.
Tell me what's going
on or i'm outta here.
Okay.
I looked in sylvan's kitchen cabinets.
Not much of a tea selection.
He's a coffee geek-- Drinks
only the best,fresh-roast coffee.
And the best fresh-roasted coffee In sylvan's
neighborhood... Is in this place here.
That's kind of thin.
Yeah,but i'm 100% confident
that it... Thank goodness.
Look,the judge warned us not to
talk To sylvan without his lawyer.
Talk?
This is two guys bumping into
each other In the coffee line.
Jane.
Cale?
That's a funny coincidence.
I told you i'd be seeing you.
Well,you look well,i gotta say.
You're in a very relaxed state.
Now confess that you killed kelly
flower,And a huge burden will be lifted.
Funny guy.
Sense of humor.That's great.
Well,maybe i did something wrong.
Sorry to,uh,bother you.
Accidents happen.
Hypnosis.Great plan.
No,that would be
silly.Hypnosis is illegal.
That was a misdirect so that i could
search his jacket pockets And find...this.
A button,fluff and some sand?
Yeah.It's a little anticlimactic.
Um,do you have an evidence baggie?
You're walking home.
Or i could just carry it.
So sylvan's financials are
clean.There's just one thing i don't get.
The end of every month,He
withdraws just over 2 grand in cash.
He has no family,no girlfriend.
Sounds like rent.
His apartment's only $900,and
he writes a check for that.
No,not his
apartment-- his home.
A place to store his tools,process
his victims,Keep his trophies.
A murder house.
And if he's paying cash,it's a fair bet
The name cale sylvan won't be on the lease.
The place could be anywhere.
Maybe i can narrow it
a little.Look at this.
This is from the sylvan murder video.
The bag he's holding--
it's from abs gym.
We show his picture around the gym.Maybe
we find someone who knows his other address.
There's a dozen abs gyms around
here.It'll take days to canvass 'em.
I'll start with the ones by the river.
The sand jane found In sylvan's
pockets-- it's river sand,not ocean sand.
- How'd you know?
- We're in sacramento.
We got a river,not an ocean.
There's only one abs gym
near the river--on dos robles.
On my way.
If you get an address,go straight to
judge hildred And get a search warrant.
We'll take down sylvan today.
Aw,shut up.
You shouldn't have embezzled
all that money,you big baby.
Time to go to work.
I don't think you're
gonna want to look at this.
What was that?
Freeze!Freeze!
Let me see your hands!Let
me see your hands!
Get your hands off of me!
Get your hands off me!
- Hook him up.
- It's not me.
I hope you brought more people.
Cheating son of a bitch.
You're okay.You're safe now.
You got it?There we go.
I sent the victim to the hospital.
He'll be okay... After three
or four years of therapy.
Good.
Yeah,that look's not so scary
when you're in handcuffs,buddy.
Either you tell us who hired you Or you're
looking at a slam-dunk death penalty.
Maybe we can come to
some kind of arrangement.
Cho,get down!
10-33.shots fired.
Man down.We need paramedics now.
G.s.w.to the chest.
Shot came from the north of
location.North of location.
Let's get a bird in here now.
The son of a bitch is dead.
Call in another team for
the back of the house.
Thanks.
That's eight bodies so far,and that's just
the ones Sylvan's clients didn't want found.
They're gonna be clearing
Missing persons cases for a month.
- Any luck on the shooter?
- Not much.
Kill shot came from that
hillside,Over two football fields away.
That's a tough shot.
So i guess whoever employed sylvan Hired
a second shooter to cover his tracks.
The thing is,how did that client know
That sylvan had become a liability?
That's a good question.
Where's jane?
This better be good.I was
catching up on my tivo.
Liar.You were reading.But what?
Progress reports?
No.
Whatever.
This is gonna be a lot of fun.
I'm going into the drabers' lair.
It's not a lair,it's an
office,and no,you're not.
Oh,yes,i am.
They seem kind of scary.You wouldn't
want me to get hurt,would you?
Don't bet on it.W-why the drabers?
A hunch.
They're key in this somehow.
You think they hired sylvan?
Well,sylvan looked the part.
Why the hell didn't you call cho?
Well,you were closer.
Call cho.I'm not even armed.
More lies.
You have at least two guns in that car.
Three?Oh,my.
You're the poster girl for the n.r.a.
I'm telling you,I've got nothing
to do with the prosecutor dying.
And the sylvan guy-- never heard
of him Before i saw him on the news.
Hello.Hi!
Gonna win big.
Gonna buy a washing machine.
She's a treasure.
You want to leave her alone?She's
a little soft in the head,okay?
You know,hank,as you were
talking to lisbon here,
I couldn't help but notice you
kept looking at your mother,
As if you were checking
for her approval.
I mean,most tough guys are scared of
their mothers,But,hank,you were quaking.
Your friend's crazier than my mom.
Digging those nails.
Plucked eyebrows,coiffed hair.
Did you do the,uh,makeover,hank?
No,didn't think so.
Time for my stories,hanky.
Okay,hanky.
You are upsetting
her,okay?So leave her alone.
Easy.
This is brilliant.
Lisbon,this is brilliant.
You--you are
a treasure.
You're running this whole
operation,aren't you?
Hank's just a figurehead
to take the heat.
Tell me i'm right.You
know,ishould havechecked the shoes.
Damn it,hank.
I told you about looking at me,didn't i?
You think you're so damn clever.
Well,clever is as clever does,And
you've just made a very stupid move.
Boys!
Oh,dear.
How clever are you now exactly?
We're cops.Just be cool.
Put the weapons down now.
You put your gun down,miss
lisbon,and you can live.
Come on.Get in.
I was right about annabelle anyway.
Congratulations.
So we're good,right?
You're not gonna put a hit out on me?
You've moved on.
That's good.
I've moved on,too.
Well,i'm glad.That's a relief.
You guys heard from jane?
- No.
Hello?!Anybody?!Hello?!
I can't really see anything.
There's kind of a draft right
here,though,if you just... Just there.
No food,no water.
This is not good.
Well,i suppose we should draw
straws To see who eats who first.
Yeah,right.Draw straws
with a professional cheat.
Why so grumpy?It's not
like we're gonna die here.
The drabers don't want us dead.
Come here and get a
little bit of this breeze.
It'll cheer you up.Come here.
It's not quite as nice as a
river breeze,But it's not bad.
You feeling that?Good.
River breeze.
Wait a minute.
I live nowhere near the docks.
Well,that's good.It's
a terrible neighborhood.
You said you called me
because i was closer,
But the h.q.is only 15
minutes from the docks.
I'm--i'm just--i'm bad with
distances,always have been.
Patrick jane,you were trying to help me.
You were.
You thought if i made a big
bust,The p.s.u.would get off my back.
You know i'm always gonna save
you,lisbon,Whether you like it or not.
I don't need to be saved.
I knew this would end a disaster
the day i signed on with you.
One day i'm gonna get fired because
of you.That's just the way it is.
Right.Well,some people might ask why
you signed on with me In the first place.
We catch a lot of bad guys.
Most days,that's enough.
- Also,i...
- I think i hear something.
- Someone out there.
- Where?
- Hello!
- Hello?
- Over here!
- In here!
Around the
front.The--the big latch.
I told you i would save you,lisbon.
Sac p.d.found jane's car
at the docks.Lisbon's,too.
- Crap.
- No sign of them or the drabers.
Call sac p.d.,i.c.e.and the coast guard.
Have them search every vehicle...
Warehouse and boat the drabers own.
Van pelt.Slow down.
Agent rigsby.
Um,s?Uno--uno
momento,por favor.
- Can you?
- I'll call you back.
It's the federales,i think.
Something about jane and a goat?
Louise willett robbed The very people
she was supposed to be taking care of,
And she spent
that money--
ipso facto,ad nauseam.Sorry,odenthal.I
need to borrow your judge for a second.
Uh,mr.Jane,we are in session.
Yes,we would have come earlier,But,uh,we
had quite a long walk getting here.
It won't take a second.
We just need One of your fancy
arrest/warrant thingies for annabelle draber.
- She'll give you the details.
- Jane,get out of here.
Mr.Jane,there are no
phones in my courtroom.
I'm very sorry.Just a minute,cho.
- I'm kinda busy.
- That's $1,000,mr.Jane.
Sure.Uh,listen,i'm kinda In the middle
of something,so i'll call you back.
$2,000.hang it up.Now!
- Really?
- $3,000.
- listen,cho,uh...
- $4,000.
- your honor,i move for a mistrial.
- $5,000.
you're not costing me another
case.Give me that phone.
No.Get your own.
Your
honor--battery?
Bailiffs,would you
arrest this man,please?
Lisbon,this... Hang on,cho.
I'm on suspension.No badge,no authority.
Oh,thanks for bailing me out.
Lisbon wasn't answering
her phone for some reason.
The judge is really
pissed,so is odenthal.
They want to make an example.
It's not just contempt of
court,jane.It's battery.
Battery against a peace officer.
Penal code section 242
"et seq."I love the latin.
You know there's 30
kinds of battery charges?
Yes.
This stuff is fascinating.
You know,i could be my own lawyer.
You're gonna represent yourself?
You represent yourself,you're an idiot.
Uh,it's actually "he who is his
own lawyer has a fool for a client."
It's much catchier.
Could be fun,cho.
This may be a,um,A
somewhat informal hearing,
But you still must respect this court,Or
you will go directly back to jail.
- Do you read me?
- Yeah,you bet,your honor.
Mr.Jane asked me to come.
Do you know why?
I have no idea.
Let's get right to it,mr.Jane.
Is it true that yesterday,
You tweaked the assistant district
attorney's nose In this very room?
Speaking of yourself in
the third person,marc,
Y-you gotta admit,sounds
a little silly.
Yes,i tweaked your nose.
Your honor,we're done
here.Mr.Jane admits the crime.
But in my defense,you
were being very annoying.
Mr.Jane,you're out of order.
You're out of order.You're out of order.
This whole trial's out of order!
Oh,come on.You gotta admit,you
walked right into that one.
Okay.
All right,my turn to question you guys.
Yes.Wait."you guys"?Plural?
Well,you're both witnesses.
Uh... When i'm cross-examing myself,
Do--do i have to stand down
there and ask the questions
And run back up here and answer them?
Mr.Jane,you stay put.
Okay.
Mr.Odenthal,you take a deep breath.
Pro perdefendants are given
a certain amount of latitude.
You know that.God help us all.
Judge hildred,are you now or have you
ever been A member of the communist party?
What?No!
Mr.Odenthal,do you own a gun?
- Wait.What?
- Are you a good shot?
Don't answer that.How about you,your
honor?You any good with a gun?
The person that killed cale sylvan,They
estimated,was more than 200 yards away.
That is a great shot.
It's why we assume there
was a second hit man.
Mr.Jane,please sit down.
Were you having an
affair with kelly flower?
No.
But isn't it true that you delight
In killing small furry animals?
You're a hunter.
This is irrelevant.
This is how we solve a murder.
Are you saying you don't
want me to solve a murder?
Of course i do.
Then answer the question,sir.
Answer it,or tell me why you won't.
I go duck hunting every season.
And what kind of gun do you use
to kill these defenseless ducks?
A 10-gauge shotgun.
And would you consider
yourself a very good marksman?
Uh,last season i bagged
a mallard at,uh,60 yards.
Oh,that's not
bad.Not--not bad at all.
10-gauge,3-inch shell.3 inches
of hell.3 inches of death.
3 1/2.
I mean,i think.Right?
So you must be a hunter,too.
No.I...
Then what's that dead
beast in your office,marc?
What is that?Did you just
get it off craigslist?
Well,i,uh,I mean,yes,i used
to hunt,just not anymore.
But you still know your
way around a gun,don't you?
Oh,relax.
It's not loaded.
You own your own rifle,don't you?
You heard that the judge had issued
a warrant For sylvan's murder house,
And you knew that you had to
silence sylvan before he talked.
Cho,get down!
You had to silence him Before
he named you as his client--
The client who hired
him to kill kelly flower.
Your honor,this is
completely ridiculous.
So prove it.
Let us search your house.We
don't find a gun,i'll apologize.
Let him do the search,marc.
No.
No?
I don't have to do that.
I have rights.
And you're obviously
prejudiced against me,judge.
And i'm going to take that
up with the chief judge.
In fact,i'm going to do that right now.
You should stay put,counselor.
- Bailiff.
- Don't move.
Sir,your hands.
The gun that killed sylvan-- A remington
700,with scope,from your garage.
Oh,and,uh... We got a warrant.
You're right.A lot
better with one of these.
You're a good prosecutor.You
know what this means.
A sniper rifle-- Lying in wait,murder
with special circumstances.
Hello,death penalty.
But if you're willing to come
clean about kelly's murder,
The d.a.will take death off the table.
That is the last and only offer
you'll get,You miserable sack of crap.
I realized the drabers didn't hire sylvan
When they didn't kill lisbon and me.
If they don't kill cops,
They're certainly not gonna kill
an assistant district attorney.
But the drabers were
connected somehow,weren't they?
'Cause their case was a career
maker,according to kelly,
And you wanted to be d.a.someday.
The draber case would have
made me a lock for d.a.
Oh,yeah.
And it should have
been me.I had seniority.
It was mine,and the bitch took it.
So you hired sylvan to kill her.
Yes.
And when sylvan was arrested,You
told him you'd fix it,that he'd walk.
As prosecutor,you had that power.
Then you hadsylvantell his
attorney to investigate me.
The whole d.a.'s office
knows how you operate.
Craziness.
I thought there was a good chance
You'd stepped over some line or other.
Turned out you had.
It's all right.He's learned his lesson.
Yeah,i have.
I certainly have,lisbon.
I won't be stopping for tea again.
...and lights out at
9:30,and your sister at 9:00.
No.
9:30.
I love you.
Bye.
You wanted to see us,ma'am?
Sit.
Before i make any final decisions,I want
to make sure i understand what happened.
You disrupted a courtroom,Assaulted
an officer of the court
So you could question him And nearly caused
a mistrial in an unrelated felony case.
Is that about right?
Yeah,that's pretty accurate.
You ignored your suspension,Confronted
a gang of criminals without any backup
And then participated In mr.Jane's
disruptions,assault,etcetera?
Yes,ma'am.
All right,then.
I'm sorry.I don't understand,ma'am.
The cbi just busted a crooked d.a.,
Rooted out corruption and solved
the murder of one of our own.
Awesome.
By the way,I.c.e.picked up the
drabers at the canadian border.
The d.a.announced he'll
try the case himself.
We should have done
that in the first place.
I'll tell the p.s.u.to
terminate your suspension.
Welcome back.
Patrick,judge hildred's clerk called.
You owe the court $16,000 in fines.
He needs a cashier's check.
The Mentalist
Season 2 Episode 19
www.tvsubtitles.net