The red light's on.
That means we're ready, yeah?
(man)
Yes.
Would you tell us why and how
a psychic becomes a CBI agent?
I'm not a psychic.
No such things as psychics.
And he's not a CBI agent.
He's a consultant.
Big difference.
"no such thing as psychics."
uh, care to elaborate?
Uh, no, not particularly.
Um, you know what?
This--this is not--
This is not a good idea,
I don't think.
Um, it's not a good idea.
(clears throat)
Okay.
Um, maybe we'll--
we'll come back to that later.
Uh, how do your cases
usually start?
Uh, a case begins with us
getting a phone call
from the A.G.'s office
to lead an investigation.
In the St. Clare homicide,
the local D.A. wanted us on it
because there were
political issues involved.
And how did
the local cops feel
bout your--
your team coming in?
We get along extremely well
with our local partners
in law enforcement, yeah.
My people can handle this,
no problem.
California Bureau
of Interference is what you are.
Interference? That's witty.
Stay out of this.
I'm sure your people are
competent, Chief Donner.
We're simply following
the A.G.'s orders.
Screw the A.G.. This case is
going to be in the news,
and you people are
spotlight hogs. That's all.
I assure you, chief--
Don't waste your time. His anger
runs deeper than you can reach.
Seriously,
don't start trouble here.
It's the last thing
we need.
The victim is
Martha St. Clare, 34--
Media relations coordinator
for the mayor of this town.
Mayor was here to break ground
on a new development,
Dug up her P.R. flack instead.
Ouch.
Yeah, victim was stabbed
twice in the chest,
But there's no blood here.
Killed elsewhere.
Home. Her nails are done.
Her hair's done.
This woman doesn't wear
sweatpants anywhere but at home.
Cho, have Van Pelt
check it out.
The killer wanted the body
to be discovered here
under the glare
of the cameras.
And likely came here
to watch the fuss.
Likely.
Maybe the camera crews
caught something.
We'll need to have them
look into it.
(sniffing)
There's bruises on her arms.
Looks like something
was ripped off her neck
during the struggle.
Is he sniffing her?
Yes.
You pay him to sniff people?
Apparently.
She's been smoking.
The nicotine patch on her arm
says she was trying to quit.
So under stress of late.
Well, case closed.
Stress got a knife
and stabbed her to death.
He's on a roll.
You're on a roll.
(sniffs) Cheap soap.
Unironed shirt. Stomach pains.
Recent loss of weight. I'm gonna
take a wild guess here.
You're angry and unhappy
'cause you're living in a motel
because your wife found out
about the woman
you're having an affair with
that you don't even care for.
You're a seething mass
of self-loathing,
And understandably so.
You son of a bitch!
Chief Donner, my apologies.
He was completely out of line.
Let--let's just get back
to the body. Sir?
♫ The Mentalist 2x12 ♫
Bleeding Heart
Original Air Date on January 21, 2009
-- Sync, corrected by elderman --
-- for addicted.com --
We've closed more cases
than any other unit in the CBI,
But we don't keep score
that way.
It's not a contest.
And you--you also lead
in the number of complaints
and lawsuits filed.
Okay, hold it.
I thought we had an agreement.
Brenda, a word.
(lowers voice) Jane's right.
This isn't a good idea.
I thought this was supposed
to be positive coverage.
It is! It will be. If we're open
and honest about the issues,
The positivity follows.
That's P.R. 101.
We're trying to solve
a woman's murder here, Brenda.
We don't have time
to waste on P.R.
Teresa, you know that we have
been crucified by the media
ever since Bosco
and his team were killed
here in our own house. When KTQZ
asked me for access yesterday,
I jumped at it,
and the deputy A.G. concurred.
Who is this guy anyway?
Totally legit
TV investigative reporter.
Mike Brewster.
He has been covering
the central valley for years.
We need this, Teresa.
Please.
Work with us.
He stays out of my way.
He can film in the office
and in the bullpen,
But not out in the field.
Thank you.
Seriously, thank you.
You won't be sorry. And it's
a two-way street, Agent Lisbon.
If there's anything
I can do for you...
There is one thing.
Okay, so this is the footage
Steve and I grabbed
of the groundbreaking.
That's the Mayor--
Melba Walker Shannon.
She plays up the folksy image,
But she can be tough as nails
if she needs to be.
Nice shoes. Chip?
No, thanks. Who's the rich guy
next to the mayor?
Oh, that's Heaton Krupp.
He's the private developer
On the project--
off the record, a prize jerk.
Who are those people?
Tree huggers.
The project's going up
on the edge
of some reclaimed land.
You mean protected wildlands.
You say "potato."
You have any other footage
of the crowds?
Not really.
Other networks might,
But gaining access
can be tricky.
It'd be good to get
a different perspective.
Cho, see if you can
get the footage.
You got it.
All right,
that's Wilson Fonteneau,
The mayor's flunky,
and here comes the money shot.
Whew.
(click)
These are
from the victim's home.
Besides the signs
of a scuffle,
the only thing that seemed to be
missing was the victim's laptop.
The murderer probably took it.
Check out this necklace.
From the photos, it looks
like she wore it a lot.
You think it could have
made the mark on her neck?
Could be. When you go
to the apartment,
do a targeted search.
The necklace is long gone.
My guess--the killer
made a souvenir of it.
Go.
Okay.
Where we going?
Mayor's office.
I don't have any problem
being in charge, no.
I mean, maybe at first
for a while,
as a woman, it was a challenge,
but the demands
of the job take over.
Yeah.
(man) Tell me
about your weekends.
You want to know what I do
on my weekends?
Yeah.
Why do you want to know that?
I mean, I have no problem having
a life, if that's what you mean.
I don't know why anybody
would say otherwise--
If they do say otherwise.
Um, I'm sorry.
What were we talking about?
Sorry for the delay.
The mayor's just finishing up
another meeting.
It's been a crazy day
around here. Can I help you?
Oh, no, I'm fine. Thanks.
Mr. Fonteneau, did you work
closely with Martha St. Clare?
For 16 months.
Martha hired me, actually.
We noticed in a lot
of recent photographs
that she had a-a necklace on
with a beautiful stone.
Yes, a topaz, I think.
It was her birthstone.
She got it Christmas of last
year and never took it off.
Do you know who gave it to her?
No.
She had a lot of meetings,
even on weekends--
Business interests,
community groups, book club.
Tomorrow is a big day.
She has a star
and 3 exclamation marks
at 11:00.
Yes.
Uh, she scheduled a briefing
with the city council.
On what subject?
I don't know, to be honest.
The mayor will know.
Was she dating anyone?
A social life--Martha?
No, she had a cat.
Ah. Yes. See?
But it died.
Right.
Excuse me.
Are you the CBI Agents?
Mayor,
thank you for seeing us.
Happy to help,
and please call me Melba.
Like the toast?
Just like. This way.
Can you tell us about
your construction project
that you were
opening yesterday?
It's the Granton Complex, yes.
We are very proud of it.
It's office and retail space
plus housing,
all built with
the latest green technology.
And what was Martha's
involvement in the project?
None, really. She...
She was my media liaison.
She was not engaged
in policy issues.
Then what was she gonna talk
about at city council tomorrow?
Oh, a press junket.
It was river rafting, I believe.
Chief Donner says your office
has received several threats
from environmental activists.
Activists?
No, they're terrorists.
They burned down vacation condos
up on the mountain.
They destroyed luxury car lots
just one town over.
They're led by a madman,
and he calls himself Jasper.
Excuse me.
Wilson,
anything else can wait.
The threats?
Yes. Um...
(voice distorted) the Granton
development is an abomination--
A hundred acres
of pristine wildlands razed,
An entire ecosystem endangered.
It must stop.
It will stop, no matter
what needs to be done.
My name is Jasper,
and I am legion.
(chuckling) Come on.
"I am legion."
that's just silly.
Silly?
Yeah.
He murdered Martha.
Well, you assume.
Yes, I do. The body was buried
at the site, for God's sake.
And that is a clear message,
isn't it?
Melba,
why would he kill Martha...
and not kill you?
It'd be
a bigger publicity coup.
Excuse me?
Uh...
What Mr. Jane is trying to ask
is whether there was somebody
with a more direct personal
grudge against Martha.
Mm...
Yeah.
No.
She was a lovely--
was a lovely person.
Oh, then why did you
dislike her so much?
I didn't dislike Martha.
Why would I employ someone
that I don't like?
That's a very good question.
When you said it,
Your jaw tensed and your eyes
went empty like a cobra.
Wilson!
I'm not saying
you killed her.
I'm just saying that you're
relieved that she's dead.
These people
will be leaving now.
Oh, I like the way you say that,
Melba-like-the-toast--
So tough and commanding.
Let me tell you something.
We are state law enforcement,
and we leave
when we want to leave.
(Lisbon)
Thank you for your time.
(Patrick)
She wants to leave.
See yah.
You blew my cool.
I swear, sometimes I think
you need medication.
It's like you've got
A.D.D. or something.
Well, "A," I'm not so sure
that A.D.D. even exists,
and "B," I was winding her up
for a reason.
Which is?
A diversion.
The message the aide brought in
Made her nervous,
so I took it.
You're stealing now?
Well, let's just
call it purloining.
What does it say?
It says "your 3:00 meeting
has now been moved to 3:15."
I'm just kidding.
It says, "9-1-1. Call now.
Urgent. About Martha."
From Heaton Krupp.
The developer
of the Granton project.
Oh, yeah.
(man) Do you enjoy
police work?
Mm...
Patrick?
Uh, yeah, I'm thinking.
Uh, mm, yes and no.
Uh, yeah, sometimes.
Sometimes not.
Forget it, Steve.
Why do you so dislike
being filmed?
Uh... (clears throat)
'cause you're
stealing my soul.
So I called the mayor.
So what?
I'm building a $20 million
complex in her town.
I call her a lot.
About ms. St. Clare?
About when I can start
construction again.
This is costing me hundreds
of thousands of dollars.
It cost ms. St. Clare
a lot more.
And I'm sorry about that.
I am. But there's nothing
I can do about it.
Martha would have
wanted us to go on.
You knew her well enough
to know that?
You're right. I'm being pious.
Maybe Martha would have said,
"screw it."
I knew her not at all
outside of business.
Really?
'cause we just got
her cell phone records,
and you called her
ten times yesterday.
You want to tell us
what you wanted
To talk about so urgently?
Seems I should get my lawyer,
have him sit in with us.
Sure. That's your right.
Tell him to bring all your
permits for the Granton project.
My permits? Why?
Why not?
And we should make sure this
stays an active crime scene--
Keep everyone out
until the case is solved.
Could take weeks.
See... we were talking
about money, okay?
$10 million in public funds
was to be released
When we broke ground. Then I
heard rumors that St. Clare
was planning to tell the city
council to withhold them.
Why?
I don't know! I mean, that's
what I was trying to find out.
But St. Clare was killed
before she could talk
to the city council.
Yes, but--
So the $10 million will
come to you after all.
What are you--are you
trying to lay this on me?
Because you're messing
with the wrong guy, officer!
We're not officers.
We're Agents.
That's quite a temper
you got there.
(glass shatters)
Look out!
(grunts)
get down, get down!
Get on the floor!
Help!
(shouting indistinctly)
I got the door!
Go, go, go, go!
(grunting)
Aah! I got you.
(glass shatters)
(coughs)
(all coughing and wheezing)
This was done by someone who
knew what he or she was doing.
(coughing)
crackpot Jasper.
He's a terrorist,
And you ain't doing jack
to catch him, chief.
I'm in charge of the town
of Salter, Mr. Krupp,
not the outlying areas.
(indistinct
police radio chatter)
Jasper's never launched
an attack here in town before.
Until now.
Hey! Check this out.
Apparently, this is
the same tag that Jasper used
in the attack on the condos.
It's good just here?
(man) that's great.
Uh, I've been in fires before.
I worked with the, uh,
arson squad in San Diego
for a couple years, so I'm not
unfamiliar with the issues.
It's never pleasant, though.
(chuckles)
Um, I mean, when you're--
When you're in it, it's--
there's no time to think.
But--but afterwards,
well...
Yeah.
It can make you think.
There was a...
There was a moment there
where, uh...
Yeah, makes you think.
It's a gift, isn't it?
Life.
You should be
grateful for it...
Make the most of it.
We have to catch this guy
before he kills someone else.
He hasn't killed anyone yet.
Not Martha St. Clare?
Eh.
Martha St. Clare was about
to stall the development.
That exactly what Jasper wants.
So why kill her?
(Lisbon) Maybe he didn't
know Martha's intentions.
But the mayor must have known.
Let's go see her.
Yeah. You guys look
into this Jasper character.
Don't bother.
He's a red herring.
What does that mean, anyway--
a red herring?
A red herring is
what you look in to
regardless of what
Jane tells you.
Anything on
the networks' footage?
They've been
throwing up hurdles--
Something about
first amendment issues.
Get the footage. I'm tired
of hearing their excuses.
We I.D. Somebody in the crowd,
maybe we get lucky.
Yes, boss.
Why am I a detective?
Why are you a reporter?
What?
Why are you making
this documentary?
It's a fresh perspective
on law enforcement.
No, I mean,
what's in it for you?
Well, uh, scoring this exclusive
is a good way to get noticed.
So you're ambitious. How long
you been doing the news here?
About eight years.
Anchor?
Mostly fieldwork.
So you're ambitious, but you
haven't gotten very far.
I, uh, I guess
that's about it, yeah.
You don't like being asked
questions, do you?
The team as a whole seems
to have a problem with that.
Is that a question?
Mike, if I can interrupt here?
Yeah.
We're clear.
Uh, there's coffee in
the kitchen, John. I'm so sorry.
Agent Cho?
Yeah?
It is the specific request
of the deputy A.G.
that your unit cooperate
fully with the media.
What's your point?
(coughs)
(Rigsby clears throat)
Ohh.
(Rigsby coughs)
Mayor Shannon,
we need to talk.
Of course. I have a meeting.
Please make it fast.
Sure. How big was your bribe
from Heaton Krupp?
That is
an outrageous slander.
You sold your approval
of the Granton project.
Martha found out.
She was gonna reveal it
At the city council meeting,
which you said was gonna be
about river rafting,
of all things.
River rafting--
from where did you pull that?
You better have
really good personal lawyers.
If you pursue
this absurd line of harassment,
I will hang you by your heels.
Did you get a slice, too,
or are you strictly wage labor?
I--
your superiors will hear
from our lawyers.
Oh,
don't bother with lawyers.
It's such a waste
of taxpayer dollars.
Just confess.
You'll feel a lot better.
In actuality, you have no proof
of this so-called bribery.
Uh, none at all.
Are all CBI Agents
this incompetent?
Have you even bothered to check
her lover as a suspect?
First you say it was Jasper.
Now it's the lover that did it.
You gonna make up your mind?
What lover? We understood
she had no social life.
I didn't know she did.
Oh, well, she did, and competent
police would have known that.
Why didn't you tell us
this earlier?
Why don't I just do your job
for you? How would that be?
Oh, just please
arrest her or something.
Nothing to hold her on.
Eh.
I'm the rookie on the team.
(chuckles)
Been here... 18 months now.
Um, it's hard work,
but this has been my dream
ever since I was a kid--
to be a Detective.
(mike) And what's been
the most surprising thing
you've learned
about this job you do?
I've...
learned a lot about myself...
As well as about other people--
stuff I wish
I didn't know sometimes.
Stuff like...
Why people do bad things
to one another.
It's mainly because of secrets.
Trying to hide the truth
chips away at your spirit.
Secrets ruin relationships.
We finally got the footage
from every news station covering
the groundbreaking ceremony.
Apparently, threats work.
These are two separate
vantage points of the mayor,
and these are feeds
of the crowd. There--that guy.
(clicking)
(Lisbon)
Can you narrow it down for us?
There's, like, 50 guys there.
The guy in the crowd there--
After the mayor
digs up the victim.
He certainly doesn't look like
he fits in. Oh, that's bold.
A Jasper acolyte.
Or the man himself.
Get with the local P.D.
See if they can identify him.
(clears throat)
(Lisbon) What is it?
Nothing. Just hungry.
So we went back
to St. Clare's apartment,
went through her closet
and realized that some
of her work shirts--
(Jane) button on the right.
Yeah, and not her size.
So the mayor was right.
She did have a lover.
Of course she had a lover.
That necklace she always wore
was obviously a romantic gift.
She'd never spend
that kind of money on herself.
Now you say so.
Very wise in hindsight.
Well, I thought
it went without saying.
It's horribly obvious when
people are in a relationship--
Impossible to hide,
try though they might.
She was
a very attractive woman.
I would not be surprised
if she had two lovers.
There is nothing here.
I'm gonna go out for lunch.
Turn that thing off, or I will
shove it down your throat.
(Lisbon) Let's take a walk,
shall we?
Come on.
I know it hasn't been
the most pleasant experience
having a camera crew here.
But you gotta cooperate--
deputy A.G.'s orders.
Yeah.
So what's the deal?
I would think out of everybody,
you'd be the most comfortable
with the cameras.
Mm.
Last time I was
in front of a camera,
things, uh,
didn't turn out so well.
Oh, God, Jane, I'm sorry.
You don't need to be sorry,
and you're right.
There's no reason not to be
civil. I'm going to apologize.
Hey, I'm sorry.
We didn't mean to be intrusive.
No, I-I shouldn't
have snapped at you.
I'm sorry. I just--I don't
like feeling spied on.
It's my own little neurosis.
You're just doing
your job, right?
Right.
Well, let me buy you a taco.
Sure.
I know you're in.
I am kind of hungry.
That's the spirit. I know
the perfect place. Vámonos.
Muchas gracias.
Mike.
Thank you.
Steve. So tell me
about news gathering.
(Steve) You get an assignment,
and pretty much--
Whoa! Whoa!
(crowd gasping and murmuring)
Did you get that?
Did you get it?
(sighs)
Keep moving.
Let's go.
I don't know where we're going,
but I hope there's a bathroom.
I am busting.
Ohh.
Definitely Jasper.
The description of the van
matches one seen
near the condo fire
and the luxury car lot
Jasper destroyed.
How long has Chief Donner
had this information?
Contact the local
and the county P.D.
On it.
We got a hit
on the Jasper associate
at the groundbreaking ceremony.
Local activists
draw the line at kidnapping.
They gave this guy up fast.
Bart Henrik. On his blog, he
calls himself a green warrior.
He's been arrested several times
for inciting a riot,
public disorder and vandalism.
Go find him. Take Rigsby.
You got it.
(crickets chirping)
(clicks)
I can see you mean business.
Uh, there's no need for
firearms. I'm not Harry Houdini.
Quiet.
Thank you.
So you're Jasper.
Well, I'm honored.
Please don't say
you kidnapped me for ransom,
because I-I doubt you'll get
$50, let alone save the whales.
No ransom. In actuality,
just a simple message--
I did not kill
Martha St. Clare
And I didn't throw that
firebomb in Krupp's office.
And you--you are gonna
tell that to the police
And to the media.
So you kidnapped me
to proclaim your innocence.
Have you ever heard
of a phone?
Oh, yeah. I see.
If you kidnap me,
and I pass on the message,
then you get a blast of
that publicity that you love.
If I am branded a killer,
everything I have fought for
is discredited.
People support me because I have
respect for all living things.
Yes. Yes,
it's a good rule of thumb
to avoid doing things
that require you to wear a mask.
And you're
such a handsome fellow, too.
How'd you know
I'm handsome?
Well, I was
just speaking figuratively.
No, you weren't.
You know who I am.
No, I have no idea.
Leave us
and don't come back.
No, he doesn't have to
go anywhere. I-I-I--
Will you listen to me?
I have no idea--
You could be Elvis Presley,
for all I know.
How did you know?
I don't know.
How did you...
Please don't do that.
Pl-- (sighs)
(grunts)
How did you know?
Well, what's not to know?
Your height,
your body language,
Your syntax.
You said "in actuality."
I mean,
who--who says "in actuality"?
Yes.
(whispers) yeah.
Very clever.
So now we have a problem.
Get that thing out of my face!
Jasper kidnapped our colleague.
Where are they?
Jasper who?
Did you know you can get more
time for kidnapping than murder?
That's crazy, right?
And being
an accessory after the fact
makes you just as guilty
as Jasper.
Man, Jasper's avenging
mother earth. That's all.
You know him well enough
to be sure of his motives.
Yes.
You know him so well you can
tell us where he might be.
Even if I knew, which I don't,
I would never betray Jasper.
"never" is a big word.
Try me.
What would Jane want us to do
in this situation, Cho?
With his life in jeopardy?
You know
what he'd want us to do.
Yep. Okay.
(Rigsby)
I guess we have to go there.
We should call an ambulance.
It's procedure.
Sure. They can set it fast,
And we can get straight back
to questioning.
Wait. Set what?
(loud clank)
Your arm--you broke it,
slipped on the stairs.
Yeah, you should
be more careful, Henrik.
Hey. Hey. A bunch of people
saw me come in here fine.
A bunch of cops,
and I'm one of them.
I saw you fall.
And every cop in this building
will say exactly the same.
(thud)
(blinds rattle)
A cabin
in the Sierra foothills,
10 miles
northeast of Salter.
Nice work.
What to do?
If I let you go now,
you'll rat me out.
If I may make a suggestion?
No, you may not.
Please, Wilson. I can help.
I cannot go to prison.
I need to finish my work.
Don't you see?
I do. I see.
Your work is very important.
But what I don't understand,
though,
Is why you were working
in the mayor's office.
Where better to study the enemy
than from within their very camp?
Did you know that the mayor
Was taking bribes
from the developer Krupp?
Of course. Who do you think
put Martha onto it?
Ah. You told her.
But why not expose the mayor
yourself or do it as Jasper?
They would know that Jasper was
inside the mayor's office.
They would soon suspect me.
I work in the shadows.
That's why I am still here,
still fighting.
I understand.
Let me help you.
Don't try to play me.
Don't go saying you won't tell
on me if I set you free,
Because I know you will.
Wilson, I am not trying to
play you. I will not play you.
I understand and respect
your intelligence.
Have a seat.
Just take a moment.
(sighs)
Wilson, look at me.
I can help you.
(whispers) how?
Look at me.
You can see
that I'm telling the truth.
I want what you want--
Peace and harmony.
Peace...
Quiet...
It's easy.
You can have it.
If you want it,
you can have it.
So peaceful.
This is Chief Donner of
the Salter Police Department!
You're completely surrounded.
Come out with your hands up!
Stay cool.
Just stay cool.
Clear!
(Rigsby) clear!
(Patrick) I'm good.
I got him. I got him.
Lisbon?
J-Jane.
Wow. I'm impressed.
How the hell did you find me
out here?
Right, because we're lost
without you?
Well, I wouldn't say that,
but I'm still impressed.
Wait. I--don't move.
Ohh.
They could have booby-trapped
the place.
We'll have the bomb squad
take a look at you.
What? (mutters) you're kidding.
You're kidding.
I'm--I'm thankful
and all that,
But just get me out of here,
and I'll tell you the story.
What story?
Ahh.
(handcuffs clatter)
So we know who Jasper is.
Fonteneau.
No trace of him. Slipped right
through the locals' hands.
He's one man,
for crying out loud.
Well, he obviously knows
those woods a lot better.
Jane, enough recovery time.
Tell us about Fonteneau.
What'd he say?
Well, he spouted
a lot of nonsense, denial.
Truth is, he took the job
in the mayor's office
yo plan targeted attacks
on new developments around town.
He and St. Clare became lovers.
Secret boyfriend.
But when St. Clare found out
about Fonteneau's secret life
as Jasper, he killed her for it,
To keep her quiet.
I'll check on the warrant
for Fonteneau's place.
Get everybody briefed,
suited up and ready to roll.
Oh, look
for St. Clare's necklace.
It was a gift from Fonteneau.
(Patrick) my guess--he took it
when he killed her. We need it.
You guys sit on the location
until the warrant comes in.
Chief Donner?
Yeah, I-it's Lisbon.
Oh, I need some aspirin.
Yeah.
(pills rattle)
Yeah, I-I just wanted--
could you hold on, chief?
Look, that's enough, guys.
We're done filming.
You know,
catching the bad guy would be
A great end of the show, make
you guys look like superstars.
Well, it'd certainly make
the deputy A.G. Very happy.
True.
All right.
You can film the bust,
But you have to do
exactly what I say.
Deal.
Meet me at Fonteneau's
at 0600 hours.
Yes, ma'am.
Hey. Chief,
we're gonna need assistance
from your entry team again.
What now?
We set a perimeter
and wait for the warrant.
Yeah, there's a lot
of this kind of stuff.
Not too many car chases.
Maybe we could, uh, ask a few
questions while we're waiting?
Uh...
Sure. If you must.
(clears throat)
Um, how did you come
to work with the CBI?
You know how.
Yes, but I-I need you
to say it to the camera.
Yeah, yeah. I-I see.
I got it.
(sighs deeply)
Um...
Well, I came to work
with the CBI
After my wife and child
were murdered.
Have you ever experienced
loss like that?
A loss of love?
There's nothing more important
than love, is there?
Well,
we're talking about you.
Yeah.
It can be very hard
when love goes away.
It's like a... A betrayal,
Almost like a violent act,
right?
Right?
I guess.
Um, why don't--why don't
we go back to, um--
When you give someone your heart
and they throw it aside,
It's natural to be angry.
Especially when you've come
to rely on them,
When your career is tied
to theirs.
I don't know what you're,
uh--
Why don't you show us
what you got in your pockets?
What?
You heard me.
No.
Why not?
Because you don't have
the right.
Okay.
Okay. I'll tell you
what you have in your pocket,
And you tell me if I'm right.
In your pocket, you have
a blue topaz necklace
that you once gave
to Martha St. Clare
when you were lovers.
You took that necklace back
after you killed her.
You were gonna plant it
in Fonteneau's house,
Prompted by
my cunningly brilliant ruse.
Aha.
Aha. That's it.
I don't know
how that got in there.
Oh, please. Don't be so silly.
Arrest him, Cho.
Get on your knees.
Put your hands on your head.
Now!
(click)
Get up.
That's for you.
And this...
Is for me.
Here it comes.
Bang. There.
You looked away.
Martha St. Clare's body
hasn't been revealed,
And you looked away, because you
knew what was gonna happen,
Because you buried that body
at that building site
and you firebombed the trailer
to try and frame Jasper.
You're too clever, Mike,
you're just too clever.
Nah.
You spout a lot of theory,
But no legal proof.
Ah.
You want legal proof?
The lab reports came back.
They found traces of Martha's
blood in the trunk of your car.
Do you want to tell us
what happened?
Rumors said
the mayor was dirty,
But there was no proof.
I knew something was up.
But... no matter
how much I pushed her,
Martha wouldn't say anything.
Nothing.
And last night,
I was going through
her computer,
Just checking on some stuff,
you know?
I found this speech
she was preparing to give,
Exposing the mayor
as corrupt,
With proof--
Facts and figures,
the whole deal.
And she kept it from me
the whole time.
This is a story that could have
made my career.
I have been waiting
for a story like this
My whole life.
And she's mad 'cause I'm
on her computer. Hello.
So she...
She said, uh, she couldn't trust
me anymore and that it was over.
The argument escalated,
And, uh,
I took my necklace back.
And then she starts
taunting me,
You know, implying that
I don't have what it takes
To be in the big leagues
anyway,
Saying I'm a loser.
She's had enough?
She's had enough? She has?
No, no, no, no.
I've had enough.
Me!
Well...
We'll take that
as a confession.
In a stunning revelation,
mayor Melba Walker Shannon
Has been arrested by the D.A.
for corruption charges...
(Rigsby) oh, yeah.
Stemming from the Granton
at Salter development.
The accuser is her
closest aide, Wilson Fonteneau,
who agreed to testify
against the mayor
in exchange for leniency
Regarding his activities
as eco-terrorist "Jasper."
This only
the latest development
In a bizarre story
of murder and greed
That has captivated
the central valley.
Hey. I was enjoying that.
Ugh. I hate how they
overdramatize everything.
Yeah, I hate that.
(deepens voice)
"captured the central valley."
(normal voice) give me a break.
Doughnuts.
Thanks.
Ladies first.
So, uh, guys?
Uh, I have something to say.
We have something to say.
Uh, life's too short
for dishonesty Van Pelt--
Grace and I are... Lovers.
No, you're not.
Um, yes, we are.
No, you are not lovers.
Uh, but we are, though.
No, you're not,
because a sexual relationship
between two fellow
bureau employees is
Strictly against the rules.
Which is why we kept it
a secret.
But we don't want to live
a lie anymore.
(inhales deeply)
come what may.
(chuckles)
Well, it's a big secret.
Well-kept.
Well, maybe you knew,
but nobody else did.
I knew. Half the building knows.
They do not.
The only person that didn't know
is glaring at you right now.
And now I have to do
something about it.
What are you gonna do?
Yeah, what are you gonna do?
I'm thinking.
(Lisbon)
Go.
-- Sync, corrected by elderman --
-- for addicted.com --
www.tvsubtitles.net