Agents?
Ma'am. Agent Hightower.
Yeah. All right.
Narcotics needs help
getting intel on a meth
house in the southwest.
- I said I could spare two of you.
- Sure. We'll get it.
Van Pelt and Cho.
What's the job?
It's hard to believe
there's intel in these.
There better be. It's
dripping on my feet.
Hightower knows about Rigsby and me.
Noticed that.
She knows, but she hasn't said anything.
Why do you think that is?
No idea.
- If you could guess.
- I wouldn't.
I can't stop thinking about it.
That's just gonna get you in trouble.
Can you help me? Can you help me?
What happened to you?
I lost my shoe.
Can you tell me where I am?
I'm--I'm gonna call
this in, all right?
- Ma'am. Ma'am.
- Can you...
Okay. All right.
We're gonna get you
some medical attention.
- Come on.
- Okay.
- Come over here and sit down.
What's your name?
Ma'am?
Grace.
Hey. She said she can't
remember who she is,
where she came from or what happened.
No I.D. Nothing on her at all.
- Where's Lisbon?
- She's on her way.
E.M.T.S think the bullet
grazed the victim's head.
I thought we should talk to her here.
She lost her shoe, so she
couldn't have walked far.
The crime scene's probably nearby.
Good thinking.
So should we wait for Lisbon or...
Hi.I'm Patrick Jane. How you doing?
My head hurts.
I don't remember who I am.
Hold my hand.
I'm gonna try and help with the pain.
Okay, I want you to concentrate
and let the pain flow
out through your arm
and into my hand.
Just let it flow, like water.
Ah, I can feel it.
Can you feel that?
Yes.
- Can you feel it flowing?
- Yeah.
The pain is flowing away.
Tell me your name.
Don't reach.
Just wait for it.
I can't.
Ah, that's okay.
That's okay.
What were you doing this
morning, before you got hurt?
- I can't.
- It's okay. Don't worry.
Tonight, then, before
my friends found you,
what were you doing?
I-I was in a room.
It's cold.
Can you see anything?
It's--it's
too dark.
Were you sitting in a chair
or were you lying down?
- Lying down.
- On the floor or on the bed?
On the floor.
There's...
dirt and straw.
It makes me cough.
- What does it smell like?
- Horses.
That's fantastic.
Grace?
Yeah. We're looking for a stable.
Yeah.
Her shoe.
Yeah, that's her shoe.
Okay.
Guys, there's a light switch right here.
The bullet creased her skull.
It didn't fracture the bone,
but a hit like that can knock
you around something wicked.
She could have been
unconscious for a while.
Shooter probably thought she was dead
and dumped her with the other bodies.
What about the amnesia?
I don't know what to tell you.
Retrograde amnesia
usually recedes with time,
But I don't know how
fast that'll happen.
Okay, what I want you to do
is just focus on the queen.
Here's the lady. Now
you saw where she is.
There's the lady.
Okay. Now tell me...
Where's the queen?
Wrong. First boy you ever kissed.
I don't know.
- What's your first name?
- I don't know. I'm sorry.
Look, there she was.
She was always there.
Right in the middle.
And the point being?
Oh, I'm just making
sure she has amnesia,
which, by the way, you do.
It's hard to lie when you're
thinking about something else.
Great.
We're checking our
missing persons database,
Then we'll run your prints.
Something'll probably come up.
- Find somebody to come in and print her.
- Okay.
- Agent Hightower.
- Morning, lisbon.
As soon as it's practical,
I want to see you, van pelt
and rigsby in my office.
I've been meaning to address
this issue for a while,
But there's been so much
coming across my desk,
I haven't had the time.
First off, neither of you is denying
you're in a sexual relationship?
- Are you?
- No.No, ma'am.
You work together, you develop feelings.
Nothing wrong with that.
But you know very well
it's against CBI rules,
And like I tell my
kids, rules are rules.
If you want to stay
together, that's your choice.
But one of you has to
transfer out of the unit.
If you both want to stay in the unit,
then you can't be together.
That's what it is.
Give me your decision
tomorrow at the latest.
Questions?
- No, ma'am.
- No.
Okay.
Lisbon, stay a moment.
Why didn't you handle
this situation yourself?
I won't defend
what I did, ma'am--
I understand these two sneaking around,
but you're their superior.
I expect more.
I'll be writing a corrective memo.
That's it.
Thank you for your time.
I don't want to talk about it.
Cho, where are we with the victims?
I verified the two I.D.s
we found at the scene.
Janine and Mitchell Langham from Chico,
Both in their 50s, no family in state.
Neighbor said that they were
hiking in Kasten State forest.
That's 100 miles from
where we found them.
Well, what about the third victim?
Same as the Jane Doe.
No I.D. Of any kind.
The coroner says he's in his early 20s.
I put his prints into the system.
Van Pelt, did you get any
hits on them? Van Pelt?
Uh, I'll check. I'll check.
The coroner thinks
that they were shot with
a high-powered rifle--
the Langhams up close,
our Jane Doe and the
unidentified male From a distance.
Do either of the Langhams have a record?
- No.
- I think we can set the Langhams aside.
I think they were
by-products, weren't planned.
- Oh?
- Yeah.
The first two victims
were shot from a distance,
I.D.s were taken.
Two victims were shot
up-close. I.D.S were not taken.
Clearly, the first two
victims were the targets.
And when the langhams
roll up to the scene,
wrong place, wrong time.
Killer shoots the Langhams, freaks out.
doesn't bother to take their I.D.S.
doesn't even notice that
one of the first victims
that he shot was only wounded.
We got a hit on the
male victim's prints.
His name's leonard
railton, Native American,
lived on the Storm River Reservation.
That's right next to the state forest.
Oh, he's been in and out of the system
since his
early teens--
mostly small stuff,
a couple of drug
busts. No family listed.
His emergency contact
is his parole officer.
Go and go show Jane Doe a picture of
- Leonard and the langhams. It's worth a shot.
- Okay.
You guys check out the trail
that the Langhams were hiking.
It sounds like something's
going on up there.
- Let's go talk to Railton's P.O.
- Hey.
There's no point in hiding
your frustration with Hightower.
I mean, sooner or later,
you're just gonna explode
with suppressed rage.
With any luck, you'll be next to me.
Well, that's what I'm worried about.
Grace.
You okay?
Sure.
No. You?
This is a good thing, okay?
No more sneaking around.
We get to decide what we wanna do.
Do we know what that is?
Let's just get through
the day, and then tonight,
We'll open up a bottle of
wine and we'll talk, okay?
Yeah. Sounds good.
- I love you.
I thought Leonard had
a chance, you know?
Good kid. Really trying
not to repeat old mistakes.
How long were you Leonard's
parole officer, Ms. Brinton?
A little over a year.
He have any family we should speak to?
No, Leonard didn't have anybody.
But his mother was Shoshone,
grew up on the Reservation.
That's why I got him to move
there after he was released.
Why the Reservation?
Leonard needed people in
his life who cared about him.
He could get that there.
It's a small community--
- not too well-off, but
tight. - Do you live there?
Mm-hmm. My father's clan
is from there. I'm shoshone.
Shoshone, uh,
with a New York
Italian/Irish thing going on,
if I'm not mistaken by the accent.
Is that from your mother's side?
I'm not the first person who needed time
to figure out who she was.
Were there any indications
That Leonard was doing anything illegal?
No. He had some problems
when he first got there,
But about six months ago,
he settled down, got a job,
- Had a girlfriend in the valley.
- What was her name?
Derrien Hopwood. I met
her a couple of times.
No record.
Good influence, I thought.
Is this her?
Uh... No, I don't know this woman.
- Positive?
- I said no.
I got it.
Does Leonard have any
friends on the reservation
- We should talk to?
- You're going on the rez?
- Yeah.
- Will the tribal police be with you?
Oh, they're aware of the investigation.
We'll keep them in the loop.
I should go with you.
Oh, that's not necessary.
As far as some of them are concerned,
You're foreigners--
foreigners with badges.
You won't get anything.
I'll get my coat.
Excellent. Well, we got
ourselves a native guide.
Yes.
Janine and Mitchell Langham.
Ring any bells?
No, but I don't really meet
people unless they're in trouble.
Well, these people got into trouble.
Been any reports of crime on the trails?
- Robberies, assaults?
- No, just, you know,
raccoons, birds, deer,
rattlesnakes, bear.
Well, I don't think a
bear shot four people
- with a high-powered rifle.
- No, bears can't do that.
Their neighbor said the
Langhams would've walked
the morningstar trail. Huh.
Morningstar is not one of
our more popular trails.
excuse me. I got--uh...
Uh, Tisdale, stand by one.
Look, I gotta go. I gotta
go up the hill there.
We have an animal control issue.
Well, we need to check
out that trail. Okay, uh...
Okay, the trailhead is right over there.
You just stay on the path.
When you get to the fork,
you go to the left, okay?
Just stay to the left. You'll be fine.
Got it. Left. Thanks.
I don't recognize any of them.
Take your time. Think about it.
I have. These people
are all dead, right?
Yes.
There's one piece of good news.
We ran you through the
fingerprints database.
You're not there.
How is that good news?
It means you're not a criminal...
or you're a very, very good one.
How's it going with the, um...
missing persons thing?
Well, no one's filed a
missing persons report
fitting your description yet,
But I'm sure it's just a matter of time.
Look, you had a job to
do, and you did it. Thanks.
You don't have to stay.
I'll stick around.
Okay.
Thanks.
I've got a lot of time invested here,
But if she leaves, we're
into this whole sexism thing
of whose job is more important.
- Like I said, it's complicated.
- No, it isn't.
- What? - Which do you want
more-- your job or van pelt?
What? It--it's
not that easy.
Sure it is. This is the fork, right?
- No, we--we took the fork. No,
I don't think that was the fork.
- I think this is the fork.
- Well, whatever. Go left.
It's not that simple.
Job or Van Pelt. All there is to it.
The rec center's the
community gathering spot.
Leonard used to come here.
This is Joseph Silverwing.
He helped to settle Leonard in here.
He's on the tribal council.
Joseph, these are the
detectives from cbi
I called you about.
Teresa lisbon. Hi.
Patrick jane.
We're investigating the
murder of Leonard Railton.
Can you tell us anything about him?
He's a good kid. Worked
hard. Stayed out of trouble.
We heard he had a job.
Down at, uh, Markham Willis's place.
It's a souvenir shop
just off the reservation.
Was Leonard having any problems?
No.
Did you hear about any
arguments or fights?
No.
Money problems? Health issues?
You're right. You really
are opening things up here.
Do you know about any relationships
- He was having off the reservation maybe?
- No.
Nice shot.
Did you guys know Leonard Railton?
I'll take that as a yes.
I'm trying to find the
person who killed him.
Do you want to help me with that?
Don't all speak at once.
Who's gonna talk first?
We don't talk to po-po.
Po-po?
I like that.
But I'm not po-po.
I'm a po-po consultant.
How about this?
I bet that I can sink a ball
before your best player can,
And he can have three chances to my one,
And if I lose... 50 bucks. Huh?
But if I win, you tell me about Leonard.
We got a deal?
Great. Who's your sharpshooter?
It's you, isn't it,
shorty? Let's do this.
Okay.
All right. First ball in wins.
You get three chances. I get one.
Okay.
And by the way, that
girl you're crushing on,
The one in the blue sweater--
it's never gonna happen.
She's into the tall guy. Good luck.
My money's on the kid.
one.
Two.
Last time. Good luck. Lucky last.
That's three.
There's a hole in that ball.
Here's the hard part.
Ooh! Schooled ya.
Okay, so, uh, what was Leonard's story?
He had money. A lot of it.
Always had the newest kicks.
Since when?
Like, six months ago.
Well, I heard he had a job.
Oh, yeah. At Willis's souvenir shop?
That's pennies.
Leonard had money.
Any idea where that
might have come from?
He wouldn't say.
But he was out in the
woods all the time,
So... We figured, you know?
Yes?
Everybody knows what
goes on in the woods.
oh, sure. The woods.
Yeah, this is not the trail.
It's over here.
Are you sure? I thought
I saw it over here.
Water tank?
Cho?
Yeah?
There's a pot plant here.
Actually, there's a whole
bunch of pot plants here.
It looks like a farm.
Which means there's probably
some bad guys with guns.
No bars. So much for backup.
There's only one shooter. You draw fire,
And I'll take him from the side.
Ready? One... Two...
Three! Go.
Rigsby! Clear!
Got it!
It's the kind of farm you
find all over public lands--
About an acre of plants,
irrigation pipes everywhere.
Must be tapping into
water from up the valley.
Did you hit the shooter?
Maybe he's in a hospital.
Didn't see any blood. I doubt it.
Do you think the ranger
knowingly directed you
Toward the pot farm? Was this a setup?
It's hard to say. We
got pretty turned around.
I'm not exactly sure
we were on the trail.
Where's the ranger now?
Up in the mountains. Supervisor says
- he's out of calling range.
- Find out when he's back.
So it looks like Leonard Railton
was working for the pot farmers.
There's a hundred ways
that could turn ugly.
Meh. If Leonard was farmi'' the weed,
He would've told his friends about it.
Whatever he was doing, he
felt shame or ambivalence.
Which takes the investigation where?
Well, we haven't spoken
to the girlfriend yet.
So go do that. You
two talk to narcotics.
See if there's a line on
marijuana players in that area.
You heard what she said.
We weren't living together
or anything, just hanging out.
So Leonard isn't the
baby's father, Ms. Hopwood?
Kai's father? No.
But leonard liked your
little boy, didn't he?
Sure.
- Leonard bought most of the toys here.
- And this, uh...
Enormous stack of infant formula.
Yeah, like, 1,000 bucks worth.
What's the story with that?
Well, it's because Kai got this rash.
It was going around, you
know? A couple of kids had it.
He had this idea it was
the powdered formula.
He made me throw all the powdered out,
which is crazy, 'cause it's cheaper,
And it's real easy to use.
All you do is add water.
How's the rash now?
All gone.
I guess he was right.
You weren't surprised to
hear about Leonard, were you?
I mean, you--you
cared for him,
But you weren't startled
to learn that he was dead.
He had money,
And not from that lame
souvenir store job.
He wouldn't tell me
where he was gettin' it.
My experience is, that means trouble.
Your best guess?
I don't know. Whatever
else he was doing...
He--he was always
good to me and Kai.
He was a good man.
You find who did this.
We'll do everything we can.
Mr. Willis, how long
was Leonard working here?
Uh... I guess about six months.
I hired him on Dolores
Brinton's recommendation.
He was a great kid, good worker.
Oh, yeah. That'what I'm talking 'bout.
Pretty great, huh?
This is fantastic.
D-do you deliver?
- As a matter of fact, we do.
- All right.
- Jane, put it back.
- What?
You heard me. Now.
- Okay.
- Now!
All right.
We think that, uh, Leonard was
getting money from someplace else.
- Any idea what that was about?
- No.
He never said a word about
it. What was he doing?
We're still working on that.
I can give you a deal on that bonnet.
Special law enforcement discount.
You're not self-conscious
about peddling your
own culture, are you?
This is not my culture.
This war bonnet is
from the Laguna people.
It has nothing to do with us Shoshone.
It's kind of a pastiche, really.
But that's what you
Americans want to buy,
so that's what I sell.
Thank you for your
time, Mr. Willis. Jane?
Jane!
I'll meet you outside.
Is there some kind of
service for Leonard?
Tomorrow afternoon, I believe.
That's such a shame.
I'm gonna take that.
And I like this one, too.
It's really beautiful. So that as well,
And, um...
This thing. I'll see if I
can get a tune out of that.
Just love those feathers.
Grace, hi. It's jane.
How's it going with Jane Doe
there?  She get a clue yet?
Mm, didn't think so.
You know, bring her down to the office.
I think we're gonna have to get
a little more interventionist.
If you start to feel dizzy
or woozy or--or anything--
Grace, quit hovering.
All right? She's fine.
I took her out of the hospital, Jane.
She's my responsibility.
I get that, but she's fine. Aren't you?
What are these?
Oh, these are pictures
of where you're from.
I don't know where I'm from.
Sure you do.
I'll lay money on the
fact that you're a local.
You have roots around here.
You visited places like this as a kid.
One of these pictures here
will mean something to you.
I get nothing from that.
What about this? Hmm?
Grace, a minute?
Oh, sure. I'll be right back.
This?
Just relax. Don't work so hard.
Look at that.
Have you ever seen a more
beautiful, more peaceful place?
It would be cool if I
could just say the word,
and you could be right there.
Listening to the birds sing...
The wind rustling through the trees...
The water lapping against the shore.
If I could just say the word.
Wayne, this couldn't wait?
This is so simple.
I love you...
More than--more than this
job, more than anything.
You got shot at today.
- You're pumped full of adrenaline.
- No, no.
Well, yes, but that doesn't matter.
I know what I want to do.
I, uh...
I talked to a guy in the
San Francisco office today.
There's an opening in
the major crimes unit.
It's only an hour and a half away.
- You mean it?
- Please, let's just do this.
I-I don't care where I work.
I-I want you.
You really mean it?
Yes, yes.
Really? Now?
Ranger Tisdale should be off
the mountain in an hour, so...
His bank records say he's
depositing 2 grand a month
over and above
his salary-- cash.
Let's go talk to him.
Tisdale.
I was gonna call you. I just heard.
Pot farm. Doesn't that beat everything?
- Yeah, right in your own woods.
- Yeah.
I've been hiking these
trails for eight years.
I had no idea. I don't
know where you ended up,
But you must've gotten
seriously turned around.
That's hard to believe
when the pot farmers are
paying you $2,000 a month.
2 th--I don't know what
you're talking about.
You're gonna have to come with us.
Nice work.
Felt good.
Send you to the farm?
I was trying like hell
to keep you away from it.
All you had to do was stay on the trail.
Is that really so hard?
So you were taking money
from the pot dealers
to protect their farm, right?
They were paying me
to direct tourists away
and let 'em know
if there were any local
cops or feds snooping around.
But that's it.
Okay, these people who got
killed--I never even saw them.
I need the names of
the people who paid you.
I can't do that.
Look, these aren't hippies
Growing weed in the forest, okay?
These are serious, serious men.
If they learn that I
gave up their names,
They'll kill me.
Look, they know you've been arrested.
They think you're
giving them up right now.
Now with these men walking
around, you're in danger.
Give us their names,
and we'll lock them up.
- No, I can't.
- It's your call.
- You got a family?
- Uh, yeah.
Well, I suggest you send them somewhere.
Not out of town--
get 'em out of state.
- Know anybody on the east coast?
- No.
That's too bad. How about overseas?
- That's a first-rate interviewer
you got there. - Thank you.
Hey, what's up?
So Rigsby and Cho tell me
there was only one dude with a gun.
- That doesn't seem like much.
- No, it's not.
So when you say, "These are not hippies,
these are serious, serious men,"
That implies many scary
men with large guns, right?
- Yes.
- So why just one?
I don't know. They
might be low on money.
I mean, the--the
crop is doing badly.
Plants are dying?
Yeah, yeah. And the word
is that it's been going on
for about six months, and
nobody can figure it out,
- and they're really kind of freaking out about it.
- I'm sure.
- Jane?
- Yeah?
Uh, I think I gotta-- I
gotta go. I'll see you later.
Thank you.
So what'd you get from the guy?
- The pot farmers didn't kill Leonard.
- That so?
- Yep.
- You certain?
Well, certainty is the mother of fools.
So all this is just...
guesswork with you?
Pretty much.
I mean, that's-- that's
what I do, I guess.
For instance, I guess
that you're married.
I'm wearing a ring.
Well, I guess that you're
married, but not happily.
Not that there's divorce
proceedings in place,
but...
possibly a trial separation.
Guess I should've put up a photo, huh?
I know you're not giving
me relationship advice,
so I have to wonder
why you would go there.
I guess it's your way of
expressing unhappiness.
Mm, could be.
I guess it's your way of saying
you're unhappy with the
way I'm handling Lisbon.
We spend a lot of time together.
And when she's unhappy,
uh, I'm less happy.
It's human nature.
Yes, it is.
I'll tell you what, Patrick.
Why don't you let me
handle my business my way
and then judge me by the results?
And I'll let you
handle yours your way...
Up to a point.
That sounds fair.
Yeah, very fair. We done?
No.
Please don't interrupt interrogations.
- It's rude.
- That's a rule, is it?
Guideline.
I'll keep it in mind.
Now we're done.
Loving those pumps.
Thank you.
Bye.
Oh, what's this? Interesting.
we need to take amnesia
girl up to the reservation.
Meet me in the parking
lot in ten minutes.
Why take her to the reservation?
They're holding a memorial
for Leonard Railton.
She should be there.
- She might remember something.
- Worth a try, I guess.
Oh, do me a favor. Hmm?
- Don't mention this to Lisbon or Hightower.
- And why not?
- Well, why complicate things?
- Complicate how?
Hell, Van Pelt, you
shouldn't have taken her
out of the hospital in the first place.
Your car, parking lot, ten minutes.
Mr. Jane, what are you doing here?
Well, we're here to pay our respects.
It's okay. We won't eat much.
Leonard had only been
with us a short while,
but if you saw him
walking a trail up at the
lakes or riding a horse,
You could see
that he was home.
So remember the old words.
When a friend dies,
We should not cry.
We should not hate someone
Or fight.
We should do right always.
And we should listen to the old words
and remember Leonard.
If anyone else has something to say...
Oh, I would.
This woman was with
Leonard when he was shot.
She has lost her memory.
So we brought her here today
to see if a face or a place or anything
could help her remember who she is.
This is kind of a sacred
momt. Is this really the time?
It'll take but a second.
Anything?
No.
Never mind. The trip
was not entirely wasted.
I was also looking at all of you
to see if anyone recognized her.
And it seems to me that somebody
here does know this woman.
And that somebody is you, sir.
Me?
I think you're mistaken.
Prove it.
How?
Look into my eyes
and hold this.
Now tell me you don't know her.
I do not know this woman.
Okay.
Um, um, okay.
It appears that I'm mistaken,
which is very good for you.
That eliminates you from our inquiry.
My apologies. Carry on. We'll
just take our seats in the back.
Thank you.
And, listen, if you-- if
you don't want us here,
then just say the word and
we'll go. Just say the word.
- I think it would be
better-- - I see it.
I see it! I see it! I see it!
I see it.
Now just relax, breathe
and tell us what you see.
There's a blue lake...
Pine trees...
A mountain...
There's a bird singing.
Tell us what's happening at this lake.
It's where the bad thing happened.
What bad thing?
Go look. They...
They left something on the shore.
- Who did?
- Go look. They left something.
They left something.
I'm sorry.
Okay, show's over. Come on.
Watch your head.
So Mr. Silverwing is gonna
complain to our superiors
in the strongest terms. Nice work.
See, that's why I didn't
bring you along--deniability.
How did you know we were here?
I had little, tiny G.P.S. Trackers
Sewn into all your suits.
For a second there, I
almost believed you. Grace?
Sorry, Jane. I had to
tell her. It's my job.
Eh, that's not it.
- Get her back to the hospital.
- Yes, boss.
She did remember
something. We have a clue.
A lake in the mountain,
something on the shore?
Could be where the murders happened.
There's over 50 lakes
in those mountains!
I'll take her back to the hospital.
Listen, I'm sorry I didn't
tell you where I was going.
I was trying to protect you.
I knew I was gonna stir things up,
- and, what, with
Hightower all-- - Don't.
Don't ever try to protect me.
I can protect myself from
Hightower or anybody else. Okay.
- Let's go back to the office.
- We could. Or we could stay here
- and catch Leonard Railton's killer.
- How are we gonna do that?
I need a cup.
Paper or plastic--
I'd prefer paper.
So Jane Doe didn't remember the lake?
Posthypnotic suggestion.
I showed her a beautiful
picture of a lake and told her
that she would remember it when
she heard the trigger phrase--
"Say the word." She remembered
the picture, associated it
with the crime and felt that
- something was left behind there.
- What something?
Well, it--it
doesn't matter.
The killer's feeling paranoid now,
so he or she will be compelled to
go back to the scene of the crime
and make sure that
nothing was left behind.
That's assuming the murder
occurred at the lake.
- Well, it did.
- Because?
Because the pot crop died,
and Leonard Railton was worried about
the water his girlfriend's
baby was getting...
Hey, it's over here.
...and the water supply for around here
comes from the mountain lakes.
Cho followed whoever left
the memorial to the lake.
- And? Who is it?
- We'll see.
Where is he?
Straight through the trees.
Hands up.
- What's going on?
- Get your hands up.
No, I-I don't understand.
What are you doing?
Rifle shell.
Where'd you get that, Mr. Willis?
I just found it.
I was gonna give it to you.
Do you think it's
connected to those murders?
That's the best you got?
Why'd you shoot those
four people, Mr. Willis?
- I didn't.  - Well, keep
in mind that two of them--
the Langhams--they were,
uh, by-products, latecomers.
But Leonard... Leonard you killed
because of what's in
the lake, didn't you?
I don't know what you're talking about.
Toxic waste.
Great, big barrels of it, I expect.
Dumped by you.
That's why the pot plants
in the valley were dying.
That's why Derrien
Hopwood's child got a rash.
Leonard was gonna tell,
so you had to shoot him and
anyone else that just happened
to come along that day.
I don't even know what to say.
That is not true.
Well, this is ground
zero for the dumping,
so the water here
must be much more toxic
- than it is down in the valley.
- That is nonsense!
Really?
Feeling a little parched? Have a drink.
No.
- No.
- Why not?
- Oh, come on. Cheers. Have a drink.
- No.
- Little sip.
- No. No, please, stop. No!
All right!
I tried to get so many ideas
across the tribal council.
But somebody didn't like it,
or it wasn't culturally appropriate,
or blah, de, blah, de, blah.
So this guy said he
needed to dump some stuff,
and did I know any place on
the rez that he could do it?
So I had Leonard take
them up to the lake.
Well, I figured with his
record, he'd take the money
and keep his mouth shut.
Well, we went well.
Got more trucks up there.
I mean, something was
finally working for me.
And then that kid in
the valley got a rash.
And Leonard was worried.
Said we were poisoning the valley,
And if we didn't stop, that
he was gonna blow the whistle.
Then I overheard him on the phone,
arranging to meet
somebody up at the lake.
So I went, too.
When did the Langhams get there?
I was cleaning up.
You know, what they doing there, anyway?
Um, they were taking a hike?
I'm sorry.
I am.
Well, that's okay, then.
As long as you're sorry.
Maybe we'll just let you go.
I'm kidding.
Got something for you.
Your driver's license.
We got it from Markham Willis.
Your name is Camille
Dillon. You live in Oakland.
You're an Internet
journalist and writer.
We contacted your family.
Your mom is on her way from Des Moines.
My name is Camille?
Apparently, you taught Leonard Railton
while he was in the juvenile system.
A little while ago, he got
in touch with you about...
Wait.
Something... something was wrong.
They were...
Someone was, uh, dumping...
- Toxins.
- Y-yes.
And he-- he wanted
people to know. He...
He called...
And he--he asked
for my help.
I
rem--
I remember him.
I remember him asking for my help.
I remember.
I remember me.
I know who I am.
Just let me finish this up,
and we'll go talk to Hightower.
Wayne...
What's up?
I love you. I do.
But I think I love the job more.
Well, job's not a problem. I'm gonna go.
You'd be leaving the unit... for us.
So?
I don't want that responsibility.
You'll hate me for it.
- Maybe not today, but someday you will.
- No, Grace, we...
I'm sorry.
You're, uh...
certain about this?
I know who I am.
Narcotics picked up the pot farmers
off the ranger's confession.
I also got a call from
a guy named Slverwing
about a stunt you pulled up
on the Storm River Reservation.
Well, I wouldn't call
that a stunt so m--
Whatever. He was displeased.
Yes, ma'am. I
filled out a p-90--
- You solved the triple, right?
- Yeah.
- Nobody got hurt?
- No.
Then the hell with him.
You got justice done.
Keep up the good work.
That was unexpected.
I'll say.
Hey, Grace.
Hi.
- You all right?
- I'm fine.
Okay, but...
Yeah, I-I just...
I just, uh, forgot my... stuff.
www.tvsubtitles.net